<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Alyeska Pipeline Service Company contracted to EMCOM Alaska Inc.</origin>
        <pubdate>1995</pubdate>
        <title>Graphical Resource Database</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Database: Multi-Resources;  The Ship Escort/Response Vessel System (SERVS) of Alyeska Pipeline Service Company (Alyeska) is currently undertaking a major expansion and update of its environmental computer database for Prince William Sound and adjoining areas on the south-central coast of Alaska. The software, called the Graphical Resource Database (GRD), is part of Alyeska's commitment to the Prince William Sound Tanker Oil Discharge Prevention and Contingency Plan. The GRD consists of layers of coastal resource digital data records (such as seabird colony sites and sea otter concentration areas) that are linked to points, lines, or polygons depicting animal distributions on computer-generated maps. The expansion and update effort is coordinated by a committee consisting of representatives from federal and state natural resource trustee agencies, citizens oversight groups, Alyeska, and oil shipping companies. The data collection and checking process is conducted in accordance with written standard operating procedures. Data are gathered from the trustee agencies, compiled into Microsoft Excel spreadsheets, and verified using quality control/quality assurance procedures. The spreadsheets are then loaded into a commercially available mapping program, MapInfo , which serves as an intermediate graphical data management tool. The data are transferred from MapInfo to the GRD using FORTRAN programs. Data is available to federal and state agencies for oil spill planning and response.</abstract>
      <purpose>Create a sensitive coastal resource database that will be held in common and mutually accessible by government trustee agencies and industry.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>19950101</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-156.5</westbc>
        <eastbc>-146.5</eastbc>
        <northbc>61.25</northbc>
        <southbc>57.25</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Geology</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Graphical</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Pipeline</themekey>
        <themekey>Environmental</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>The database is the property of Alyeska. It distributes it to wildlife trustee agencies for oil spill response and planning.</accconst>
    <useconst>Use is limited to oil spill response and planning.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Oakley, Karen</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>1011 East Tudor Road</address>
          <city>Anchorage</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99503</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-786-3579</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>karen_oakley@nbs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Oakley, Karen</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>1011 East Tudor Road</address>
          <city>Anchorage</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99503</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-786-3579</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>karen_oakley@nbs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20020429</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>The database is the property of Alyeska. It distributes it to wildlife trustee agencies for oil spill response and planning.</metac>
    <metuc>Use is limited to oil spill response and planning.</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
