<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>
          <li>Alexander V. Bugae of KamchatNIRO, Kamchatka Fisheries &amp; Oceanography Inst., Fisheries State Committee of Russia, Petropavlovsk-Kamchatski, Russia</li>
          <li>North Pacific Anadromous Fish Commission</li>
        </origin>
        <pubdate>20041001</pubdate>
        <title>
          Scale Pattern Analysis Estimates of Age and Stock Composition of Sockeye Salmon
          <em>Oncorhynchus nerka</em>
          in R/V
          <em>TINRO</em>
          Trawl Catches in the Western Bering Sea and Northwestern Pacific Ocean in September-October 2002
        </title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>Scale pattern analysis was used to estimate the age and stock composition of immature sockeye salmon in R/V TINRO trawl catches in the western Bering Sea and northwestern North Pacific Ocean in fall (September-October) 2002. Baseline data from adult sockeye salmon in Asia and North America (ages 1.3 and 2.3 in 2001-2002) were used to estimate the stock composition of dominant age groups (1.1, 2.1, 2.1, and 2.2) of immature fish in the R/V TINRO samples. Based on similarity in scale patterns the baseline data were grouped into four stock complexes: (1) West Kamchatka, (2) East Kamchatka, (3) Chukotka, and (4) Alaska (Bristol Bay)/Northeast Kamchatka. The mean accuracies of 100% simulations of these baselines ranged from 92.4%-93.5%. The results indicate that Asian stocks dominated R/V TINRO catches across the entire region (67-95% of age-.1 fish, 77-89% of age-.2 fish). Alaska /Northeast Kamchatka stocks occurred only in Bering Sea catches, and estimates for these stocks were highest in district 8 (33% of age .1 fish, 23% of age .2 fish), which was the district located closest to the coast of Alaska. East Kamchatka was the dominant Asian stock (44-69% of age-.1 fish, 42-73% of age- .2 fish). West Kamchatka stocks were prevalent only among age-.2 fish (27-42%). Chukotka stocks occurred only in the Bering Sea, and were prevalent only among age-.1 fish (12-21%). In general these results are corroborated by the results of previous studies of the distribution of immature Asian and American sockeye salmon during their fall feeding migrations in the western Bering Sea and northwestern North Pacific Ocean. Nevertheless, the stock composition estimates reported in this document are considered preliminary, as final estimates will be made using brood-year specific scale baselines from adult returns in 2003 and 2004.</p>
        <p>[Reference: Bugaev A.V. 2004. Scale pattern analysis estimates of the age and stock composition of sockeye salmon Oncorhynchus nerka in R/V TINRO trawl catches in the western Bering Sea and northwestern Pacific Ocean in September-October 2002 (NPAFC Doc. 763) 26 p. KamchatNIRO, Kamchatka Fisheries&amp; Oceanography Inst., Fisheries State Commit. of Russia, Naberezhnaja Street 18, Petropavlovsk-Kamchatski, Russia.]</p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>To report age and stock composition estimates of immature sockeye salmon in the western Bering Sea and northwestern North Pacific Ocean.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20020901</begdate>
          <enddate>20021009</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>156</westbc>
        <eastbc>-163.5</eastbc>
        <northbc>65</northbc>
        <southbc>52.5</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Fish</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Scale</themekey>
        <themekey>Sockeye Salmon</themekey>
        <themekey>Western Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Northwestern Pacific Ocean</themekey>
        <themekey>Kamchatka</themekey>
        <themekey>Chukotka</themekey>
        <themekey>Bristol Bay, Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20050225</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>None</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
