<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>University of Alaska Fairbanks (UAF), School of Fisheries and Ocean Sciences (SFOS), Institute of Marine Science (IMS)</origin>
        <pubdate>Planned</pubdate>
        <title>Progress Report (2001) on Proposal "Pilot Study on the Use of Airborne Lidar and Digital Imagery for Surveys of Epipelagic Fish and Associated Biological Features in the Southeastern Bering Sea and North Pacific Ocean"</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>We will conduct a pilot study on the use of airborne lidar (Light Detecting And Ranging) and 3-chip digital video to assess epipelagic biological features such as forage fish
schools, zooplankton, large individual fish (e.g., salmon), marine mammals and seabirds. The results of this study are designed to supplement new and ongoing research in the Bering Sea and North Pacific, addressing several of the NPMR issues including monitoring, forage fish and apex community ecology, and effects of climate change on the biology of the systems. This study falls in the categories of remote sensing and field studies.

A lidar produces short pulses of laser light which pass through the water's  surface and reflect off biological features in the water column, and processes the returning signal. When mounted along with a video camera in a down-looking configuration from the
belly of an aircraft, we can use the combined data to produce a three dimensional array of the biological features. When conducted over ground survey transects that include
oceanography, net catches, acoustics, and bird and mammal counts, the processed lidar and video images can be properly interpreted and related to ocean conditions. We propose to overfly ground survey transects, collect continuous spatial data within each
transect, and replicate the surveys both during the day and at night. We plan to conduct these surveys synoptic with ongoing ground survey programs (including Inner Fronts, US GLOBEC and/or Ocean Carrying Capacity).

This technique could overcome many of the shortcomings of traditionally applied technology. 
Those include: 
1) the lack of spatial resolution, 
2) difficulty in performing synoptic data collection, 
3) a mismatch in comparing temporal and spatial scale (due to the speed of vessels versus the time frame of biological activity bursts or diurnal patterns), and 
4) high cost (ground surveys can be reduced). In California, lidar surveys have been
evaluated for assessments of pelagic sardines and anchovy as a way to reduce the shipboard time involved due to the low relative cost of remote sensing at high speeds.

In order to fully evaluate this  technique in Alaskan waters, we intend to conduct surveys in two separate oceanographic regions, namely the Bering Sea and northern regions of the Pacific Ocean adjacent to the Alaskan coast. 

This project also includes;

Brenda Norcross 
University of Alaska Fairbanks 

James Churnside 
Environmental Technology Laboratory, NOAA
An NPMR project</abstract>
      <purpose>Progress Report (2001) on proposal "Pilot Study on the Use of Airborne Lidar and Digital Imagery for Surveys of Epipelagic Fish and Associated Biological Features in the Southeastern Bering Sea and North Pacific Ocean"</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19990701</begdate>
          <enddate>20010731</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Planned</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>167</westbc>
        <eastbc>-163</eastbc>
        <northbc>67</northbc>
        <southbc>53</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Fish</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Progress Report</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Lidar</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Unknown</accconst>
    <useconst>Unknown</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Brown, Evelyn D.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 757220</address>
          <city>Fairbanks</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99775-7220</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-474-5801</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>ebrown@ims.uaf.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Brown, Evelyn D.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 757220</address>
          <city>Fairbanks</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99775-7220</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-474-5801</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>ebrown@ims.uaf.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20000202</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Unknown</metac>
    <metuc>Unknown</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
