<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), Alaska Fisheries Science Center (AFSC)</origin>
        <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
        <title>Juvenile Sablefish Tagging Studies in St. John Baptist Bay (By Tom Rutecki: AFSC Quarterly Report: Jul. - Sep. 2002)</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Ten sonic tags were surgically implanted into juvenile, age-1+ sablefish captured in St. John Baptist Bay, in coastal southeastern Alaska, during 1-6 June 2002.  The tags were programmed to acoustically transmit a record of temperature and depth experienced by the tagged fish.  Mobile acoustic receivers located onboard the NOAA ship John N. Cobb were used to monitor the fishﾒs movements and habitat utilization in rearing locations in the bay.</abstract>
      <purpose>To use the sonic tags to provide information on juvenile sablefish behavior and habitat use in nearshore rearing areas and timing and duration of the emigration from nearshore rearing habitat. Fixed acoustic receivers located along corridors leading from the rearing locations to the open ocean will be used to monitor the timing of juvenile emigration from their nearshore rearing habitat to the more open waters of the Gulf of Alaska. T utilize archival electronic tags in addition to sonic tags to provide information on juvenile sablefish movement and habitat use during their transition from nearshore rearing areas to offshore areas where they are intercepted by the fishery.  Archival tags will be used to record the temperature and depth experienced by juvenile sablefish from the time they leave the nearshore rearing areas at age 1+ or greater until the time they recruit to the fishery at age 2+ or greater.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20020601</begdate>
          <enddate>20020606</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-135.6</westbc>
        <eastbc>-135.58</eastbc>
        <northbc>57.3</northbc>
        <southbc>57.2</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Fish</themekey>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Juvenile Sablefish</themekey>
        <themekey>Sonic Tagging</themekey>
        <themekey>St. John Baptist Bay</themekey>
        <themekey>Coastal Southeastern Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>Contact the agency.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Rutecki, Tom</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing Address</addrtype>
          <address>11305 Glacier Highway</address>
          <city>Juneau</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99801</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-789-6051</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>907-789-6094</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Tom.Rutecki@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Rutecki, Tom</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing Address</addrtype>
          <address>11305 Glacier Highway</address>
          <city>Juneau</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99801</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-789-6051</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>907-789-6094</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Tom.Rutecki@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20030205</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>Contact the agency.</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
