<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>University of Washington (UW), Joint Institute for the Study of Atmosphere and Ocean (JISAO)</origin>
        <pubdate>1995</pubdate>
        <title>An Indirect Estimate of the Diurnal Cycle in Upper Ocean Turbulent Heat Fluxes at the Equator, 140ﾰW</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The diurnal cycle in the heat budget of the upper equatorial Pacific Ocean is studied using 26 days of special high-resolution oceanographic and meteorological observations from a current meter mooring at 0°, 140°W. The focus is on the turbulent heat fluxes at the base of the mixed layer, which are calculated as a residual in the mean diurnal heat budget. The inferred downward heat flux at the base of the mixed layer is ~150 W m, averaged over the mean diurnal cycle, and ranged from near zero in the morning and early afternoon to ~200 W m during the late afternoon until dawn. The magnitude and phasing of the mean diurnal cycle were similar for different definitions of the mixed layer depth. The inferred residual turbulent fluxes were used also to estimate the mean diurnal cycles in vertical eddy diffusivity and turbulent dissipation rate. These turbulence parameters and the heat fluxes from which they were derived have magnitudes that are broadly consistent with those estimated previously from direct microstructure measurements.</abstract>
      <purpose />
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-140</westbc>
        <eastbc>-140</eastbc>
        <northbc>0</northbc>
        <southbc>0</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Bond, Nicholas A.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>4909 25th Ave NE, first floor - (JISAO)</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98195-4235</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6459</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Nickolas.A.Bond@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Bond, Nicholas A.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>4909 25th Ave NE, first floor - (JISAO)</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98195-4235</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6459</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Nickolas.A.Bond@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20010305</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
