<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>McGill University, Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences and Centre for Climate and Global Change Research</origin>
        <pubdate>19970718</pubdate>
        <title>Moisture Transport Diagnosis of a Wintertime Precipitation Event in the Mackenzie River Basin</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Wintertime precipitation events in the Mackenzie River basin (MRB) play an
     important role in the hydrology of the region because they contribute substantially
     to water storage prior to the spring runoff maximum. The Mesoscale
     Compressible Community (MC2) Model is used to simulate a representative
     wintertime MRB precipitation event. The MC2 simulation, gridded analyses, and
     raw observations are used to (i) document meteorological conditions associated
     with the precipitation event, (ii) assess the ability of the model to reproduce the
     precipitation event and antecedent large-scale moisture transport, and (iii) identify
     which planetary- and synoptic-scale features are responsible for the observed
     moisture transport using piecewise quasigeostrophic potential vorticity (QGPV)
     inversion.

       Precipitation in the MRB develops north of an intense frontal boundary as a
     southwesterly flow of moisture originating over the Pacific Ocean is lifted over
     cold, dense arctic air near the surface. A lee cyclone forms along the frontal
     boundary as an upper-tropospheric disturbance approaches from the west. The
     MC2 model adequately represents the lee cyclone formation, the observed
     precipitation event, and large-scale moisture transport, as determined through
     comparison of the model output with analyses and raw observations. A plume of
     moisture advances northeastward from the subtropical Pacific Ocean toward the
     MRB during the 24ﾖ36-h period prior to the precipitation event. Piecewise
     QGPV inversion demonstrates that the background climatological flow and a
     cyclonic QGPV anomaly located over the eastern Pacific Ocean are associated
     with the initial moisture transport into the Gulf of Alaska. Later, a second cyclonic
     QGPV anomaly centered over the Gulf of Alaska is associated with moisture
     transport from over the Gulf of Alaska into the MRB. The moisture flux is
     generally largest in the lower troposphere owing to the larger concentration of
     water vapor there. The Rocky Mountains, located west of the MRB, block much
     of the eastward moisture transport below the 800-hPa level. Moisture transport in
     the layer between 700 and 800 hPa is therefore crucial for MRB precipitation in
     situations where the moisture originates over the Pacific. QGPV inversions based
     on a vertically partitioned QGPV field indicate that QGPV anomalies located
     below the dynamic tropopause are associated with larger moisture transport at
     the 700-hPa level than their tropopause-based counterparts.</abstract>
      <purpose>To report on the moisture Transport Diagnosis of a Wintertime Precipitation Event in the Mackenzie River Basin</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19970718</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.4</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Meteorology</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Lackmann, Gary M.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>3600 McTavish, Office 1200</address>
          <city>Montreal</city>
          <state>Quebec</state>
          <postal />
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Lackmann, Gary M.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>3600 McTavish, Office 1200</address>
          <city>Montreal</city>
          <state>Quebec</state>
          <postal />
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990204</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
