<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Moss Landing Marine Laboratories</origin>
        <pubdate>Planned</pubdate>
        <title>Determining the Age and Growth of Three Species of Deep-Sea Coral from the Davidson Seamount off Centeral California</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Recent investigations of the Davidson Seamount off central California using a remotely operated vehicle have revealed communities rich with deep-sea corals.  During these observations several corals were collected and three colonies were made available for an age and growth study.  The colonies examined in this study were identified as bubblegum coral (Paragorgia sp.), precious pink coral (Corallium sp.), and bamboo coral (Keratoisis sp.).  Age was estimated from growth zone counts made in skeletal cross sections.  These age estimages were used to estimate growth rates, and ultimately colony age and perhaps longevity.  To validate the growth rate estimate from growth zone counts a radiometric method called a lead-210 dating was used to determine an independent growth rate for each colony.  Agreement of growth rates derived from growth zone counts and lead-210 dating were used as an indicator of age estimate accruacy.  Growth rates determined for each species were quire different.  The bubblegum coral had a relatively high growth rate, with the precious pink coral being somewhat intermediate and the bamboo coral being the slowest growing

[ Co-PIs: Gregor M. Cailliet, Allen H. Andrews ]  [ An NPMR project ]  

[ Reference: Title: Andrews, A.H., G.M. Cailliet, L.A. Kerr Ferrey, K.H. Coale, C. Lundstrom, and A. DeVogleare. In preparation.  Determining the age and growth of three species of deep-sea coral from the Davidson Seamount off central California. Proceedings of the Second International Symposium on Deep Sea Corals. Erlangen, Germany. September 8-13. ]</abstract>
      <purpose>Follow up work in the realm of deep sea corals.  To use red tree coral as a climate record for the Gulf of Alaska.  Reference Metadata ID 1637.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>In Progress</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-122.95</westbc>
        <eastbc>-122.58</eastbc>
        <northbc>35.85</northbc>
        <southbc>35.5</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Biology</themekey>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Davidson Seamount</themekey>
        <themekey>California, U.S.A.</themekey>
        <themekey>Coral</themekey>
        <themekey>Radiometric</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Unknown</accconst>
    <useconst>Unknown</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Cailliet, Gregor M.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>8272 Moss Landing Road</address>
          <city>Moss Landing</city>
          <state>CA</state>
          <postal>95039-9647</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>831-632-4432</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>831-632-4403</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cailliet@mlml.calstate.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Cailliet, Gregor M.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>8272 Moss Landing Road</address>
          <city>Moss Landing</city>
          <state>CA</state>
          <postal>95039-9647</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>831-632-4432</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>831-632-4403</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cailliet@mlml.calstate.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20000501</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Unknown</metac>
    <metuc>Unknown</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
