<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>University of Washington (UW), Applied Physics Laboratory (APL)</origin>
        <pubdate>199009</pubdate>
        <title>Effect of Entanglement on Populations of Northern Fur Seal</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>
          This report addresses several issues relative to the effect of entanglement in net-debris on northern fur seal populations.  The work reported here examined several aspects of entanglement including:
          <br />
          <ul>
            <li>a review of land-based methods used to estimate additional mortality of seals entangled in small net debris.</li>
            <li>a review of methods and reanalysis of data to ascertain the rate of change of the fur seal population since significant entanglement was observed (1965)</li>
            <li>an analysis of the relive spatial distribution of debris and seals, based on pelagic sightings of seals and debris</li>
            <li>a review of available debris sighting data and an attempt to apply in transect methods to estimate debris abundance and its spatial distribution.</li>
            <li>modeling of the seal population with special emphasis on entanglement rate and entanglement mortality rate to examine the plausibility of entanglement and, through a sevnsitivity study, indicate the relative importance of, and probably interaction between, entanglement related parameters.</li>
          </ul>
          This report has been organized as a collection of separate sections, some of which are now submitted papers.
        </p>
        <p>[Reference: Swartzman, Gordon, Christine Ribic, and Chisheng Huang. 1990. Effect of entanglement on populations of northern fur seal (Callorhinus ursinus).  Final report to the National Marine Mammal Laboratory.] This report can be found at the National Marine Mammal Laboratory Library, Seattle, WA under "reprint file".</p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>A report on the effect of entanglement on populations of northern fur seal.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Mammals</themekey>
        <themekey>Biological Effects</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Fur Seals</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Engineering</themekey>
        <themekey>Entaglement</themekey>
        <themekey>Callorhinus ursinus</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NMML Library</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-546-4013</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6615</cntfax>
        <cntemail>nmml.library@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NMML Library</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-546-4013</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6615</cntfax>
        <cntemail>nmml.library@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990128</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>None</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
