<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>
          Hideji Tanaka, Nancy Navis, Takeshi Onuma, Makoto Yamada, Yuzo Yamamoto, and Sadamasa Tsuchiya of Hokkaido National Fisheries Research Institute
          <br />
          North Pacific Anadromous Fish Commission (NPAFC)
        </origin>
        <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
        <title>
          Salmonid Disk Tagging Aboard the R/V
          <em>Wakatake maru</em>
          in the Central North Pacific Ocean and Bering Sea during the Summer of 2002 (BASIS Japan)
        </title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>The Wakatake maru (666 gross tons) departed Kushiro on June 8, 2002 and returned on July 21, 2002. There were 28 experimental fishing stations during the cruise. Nineteen fishing stations were located in the vicinity of 180º longitude from 41ºN to 58º30ﾒN latitude, and nine operations were conducted in the international waters of the central Bering Sea.</p>
        <p>Live salmon caught in a healthy condition were put into a recovery tank soon after removal from the longline. Fish were tagged with two disk tags issued by the Fisheries Agency of Japan (JFA) and the Fisheries Research Institute, University of Washington (FRI). Both disk tags were placed on one plastic cinch strap and applied to the fish anterior to the dorsal fin. The fork length was measured and two scales were collected before the fish was released to the sea.</p>
        <p>A total of 1042 tagged salmonids were released to the North Pacific Ocean (n = 42) and Bering Sea (n = 1000). The releases included 974 chum, 28 sockeye, 21 chinook, 15 coho, 2 pink salmon, and 2 steelhead trout. Of these fish, 51 salmon at St.27 and 28 were released with only JFA disk tag because we exhausted our supply of FRI disk tags at St.27.</p>
        <p>
          [Reference: Tanaka, H, N. Davis, T. Onuma, M. Yamada, Y. Yamamoto, and S. Tsuchiya. 2002. International salmon research aboard the R/V
          <em>Wakatake maru</em>
          in the central North Pacific Ocean and Bering Sea during the summer of 2002. (NPAFC Doc. 622). 21 p. Hokkaido National Fisheries Research Institute, Fisheries Research Agency, 116 Katsurakoi, Kushiro 085-0802, Japan.]  This report is available at http://www.npafc.org/BASIS/622(Japan).pdf
        </p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>
        <p>
          To monitor the stock condition of salmon (
          <em>Oncorhynchus</em>
          spp.) in the central North Pacific Ocean and Bering Sea.
        </p>
      </purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20020608</begdate>
          <enddate>20020721</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>150</westbc>
        <eastbc>-178</eastbc>
        <northbc>58.5</northbc>
        <southbc>39</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Fish</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Central North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Salmon</themekey>
        <themekey>Disk Tagging</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Source.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20050225</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Source.</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
