<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>University of Alaska Fairbanks (UAF)</origin>
        <pubdate>20010101</pubdate>
        <title>Bubble Gum Walrus - Alaska Sea Grant Radio Show</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Marine mammals have evolved a number of strategies to stay warm in the frigid Arctic. Seals have short dense fur over a layer of blubber, while polar bears have thick, long fur that traps air close to their skin. But walrus have chosen a different path to staying warm, as Doug Schneider reports in this week's Arctic Science Journeys Radio.</abstract>
      <purpose>Recently, I saw walruses up close, at one of the state's best places for seeing these two-ton tusked monsters: Round Island, in Alaska's Bristol Bay.

From a vantage atop a cliff overlooking the Bering Sea, I saw hundreds of walrus crowded onto rocky beaches below. An amazing sight, male walrus gather here each
 summer to rest and shed their skin. As walruses clamored and stumbled over each other, my eye caught something odd gliding beneath the ocean surface, heading toward
 shore. Seconds later, it showed itself to be another walrus. But this one was very different. Rather than brown in color like the ones on the beach this one was a pale
 gray, almost white. After a few minutes ashore, the walrus turned the color of bubble gum.

With me at the time was Dr. Sue Hills, a marine scientist from the University of Alaska Fairbanks. She told me this walrus had recently returned from feeding far out to sea.
The cold water, she said, made their skin turn pale. To learn more, she suggested I talk to Kathy Turco, who'd done her master's degree on walrus a decade ago.

These days, Kathy Turco is a laboratory technician at the university. She also runs a sound recording business and travels extensively, collecting sound effects for Hollywood
 movies, television specials and radio programs. I asked her about Round Island's strangely colored walrus.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>20010101</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-166</westbc>
        <eastbc>-157</eastbc>
        <northbc>59</northbc>
        <southbc>56</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Acknowledgement of data source publication required.</accconst>
    <useconst>Acknowledgement of data source publication required</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Turco, Kathy</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Box 83305 - University of Alaska Fairbanks</address>
          <city>Fairbanks</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99708</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-455-4286</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>fnkrt@uaf.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Turco, Kathy</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Box 83305 - University of Alaska Fairbanks</address>
          <city>Fairbanks</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99708</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-455-4286</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>fnkrt@uaf.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20020225</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Acknowledgement of data source publication required.</metac>
    <metuc>Acknowledgement of data source publication required</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
