<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>University of Washington (UW), Department of Atmospheric Sciences</origin>
        <pubdate>19970318</pubdate>
        <title>A Polar-Low Development over the Bering Sea: Analysis, Numerical Simulation, and Sensitivity Experiments</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>A polar low that developed over the western Bering Sea on 7 March 1977 and
     tracked across St. Paul Island is investigated using observations and the
     Pennsylvania State UniversityﾖNational Center for Atmospheric Research
     Mesoscale Model Version 5 (MM5). A series of fine-mesh (20 km) simulations
     are performed in order to examine the structure of the cyclone and the airflow
     within it and to determine the physical processes important for its development.
     Observations show that the low formed near the ice edge in a region of moderate
     low-level baroclinicity and cold-air advection when an upper-level trough, or lobe
     of anomalously large potential vorticity (PV), broke off from a migratory,
     upper-level cold low over Siberia and advanced into the region.

       A full physics model experiment, initialized 24 h prior to the appearance of the
     polar low, produced a small, intense cyclone having characteristics similar to the
     observed low. The simulated low more closely resembled an extratropical cyclone
     than a typical circularly symmetric hurricane, possessing a thermal structure with
     frontlike features and an asymmetric precipitation shield. Although the simulated
     low developed southeast of, and earlier than, the observed low, the basic
     similarity of the observed and modeled systems was revealed by a comparison of
     the sequence of weather elements at a point in the path of the simulated low with
     the sequence of observations from nearby St. Paul Island, Alaska.

       A series of experiments was performed to test the sensitivity of the simulated
     polar low development to various physical processes. Four experiments of 48-h
     duration each were initialized 24 h before the low appeared. In the first
     experiment, in which surface fluxes were turned off, the low failed to develop. In
     the second experiment, in which the fluxes were switched on after a 24-h delay,
     only a weak low formed. In the third experiment, in which the ice edge was
     shifted a degree of latitude to the north, thus increasing the overwater fetch of the
     cold air, the lowﾒs evolution was slightly altered but the final outcome was little
     changed. A fourth high-horizontal resolution experiment (6.67-km spacing)
     displayed more plentiful and sharper mesoscale features but on the storm scale
     yielded results that were similar to those of the full-physics run. A full-physics
     experiment initialized 24 h later, at the time the low first appeared, and run for 24
     h, produced a system of similar intensity to that in the 48-h full-physics run but
     somewhat better positioned. Corresponding sensitivity experiments showed that
     with both surface fluxes and latent heating omitted, the low weakened and nearly
     died away. Experiments retaining only surface fluxes in one case and only latent
     heating in the other, produced similar cyclones of moderate depth.

       The results suggest that the development of some, if not most, polar lows can
     be regarded as fundamentally similar to that of midlatitude ocean cyclones. In both
     cases a mobile upper-level PV anomaly interacts with a low-level thermal or PV
     anomaly produced by thermal advection and/or diabatic heating. The polar low
     lies at the end of the spectrum of extratropical cyclogenesis in which concurrent
     surface fluxes of sensible and latent heat and the immediately ensuing
     condensation heating in organized convection dominate the development of the
     low-level anomaly.</abstract>
      <purpose>To report on the Polar-Low Development over the Bering Sea: Analysis, Numerical Simulation, and Sensitivity Experiments</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19970318</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Polar Albedo</themekey>
        <themekey>Analysis</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Bresch, James F.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>University of Washington - Dept. Atm. Sci.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98818</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Bresch, James F.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>University of Washington - Dept. Atm. Sci.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98818</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990204</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
