<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>B.L. Wing of Alaska Fisheries Science Center, Alaska and D.R. Barnard of Alaska Department of Fish and Game, Alaska</origin>
        <pubdate>2004</pubdate>
        <title>A Field Guide to Alaskan Corals</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>This guide presents updated keys to genera and species of corals known from Alaskan waters.  The key rely on macroscopic characters as much as possible.  Where microscopic examination is required to identify species, the indentification is carried only to genus or group of genera.  Keys to the Octocorals (soft corals, gorgonian corals, sea pens, and sea whips), Scleracatinia (cup corals), and Antipatharia (black corals)  are carried only to genera.  The key to Hydrocorals are to species.  Photograhps of representatives of each genus are used to assist in identification.  Where possible, photographs of fresh specimens are included.  A brief glossary defines specialized terms used to describe corals.  Presented is a list of the 105 coral species reported from Alaska.  Some of the reported species may be synonyms or misidentifications.</p>
        <p>[Reference: Wing, B. L., and D. R. Barnard. 2004. A field guide to Alaska corals.  U.S. Dep. Commer., NOAA Tech. Memo.  NMFS-AFSC-146, 67 p.]</p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>To provide informal scientific and technical guide of Alaskan corals, especially to fisheries observers aboard vessels where microscopes may not be available.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-180</westbc>
        <eastbc>-130</eastbc>
        <northbc>56</northbc>
        <southbc>30</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Genera</themekey>
        <themekey>Species</themekey>
        <themekey>Guide</themekey>
        <themekey>Coral</themekey>
        <themekey>Cold Water Coral</themekey>
        <themekey>Depp-sea Coral</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Source.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Wing, Bruce</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>11305 Glacier Highway</address>
          <city>Juneau</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99801-8626</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-789-6043</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>907-789-6094</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Bruce.Wing@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Wing, Bruce</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>11305 Glacier Highway</address>
          <city>Juneau</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99801-8626</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-789-6043</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>907-789-6094</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Bruce.Wing@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20050120</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Source.</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
