<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (OAR), Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory (PMEL)</origin>
        <pubdate>1988</pubdate>
        <title>Morphology, Structure and Resource Potential of the Blanco Transform Fault Zone</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>A series of rhombohedral basins along the 350-km-long Blanco transport fault zone (BTFZ) are oceanic analogs to pull-apart basins along major divergent wrench
fault systems on the continent. In plan view, the BTFZ is similar to the Gulf of California; a series of long strike-slip faults (as much as 100 km long) are separated by
short extensional basins (&lt; 20 km) that have internal structures oriented at a large angle to the master faults. In the Blanco region, continual reorientation of the
transform fault in response to changes in plate motion during the past few million years provides a mechanism for the formation of these basins. A series of
back-tilted, inward-facing fault blocks covered with uplifted turbidite beds brackets the largest of the depressions (Cascadia), which may be a sea-floor spreading
center. Deformed Holocene and Pleistocene turbidite sequences are present within the depression, and there is substantive morphologic and sedimentologic
evidence of rapid Holocene subsidence of the floor of the Cascadia Depression. A large water-column methane signal of unknown origin is present, but to date there
is no direct evidence of a sea-floor hydrothermal system. However, the probable presence of intrusive bodies within the sedimentary sequence of the Cascadia
Depression could give rise to sediment-hosted sulfide bodies such as those of the Guaymas Basin in the Gulf of California. The depressions at either end of the
BTFZ (the Gorda and Blanco Depressions) are largely unexplored, but sulfide-veined greenstone breccias and hydrothermal sediments have been recovered from
them. Oceanic transform fault zones such as the Blanco may also have hydrothermal systems associated with deep fracturing and high topographic relief.</abstract>
      <purpose />
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-130</westbc>
        <eastbc>-126.5</eastbc>
        <northbc>45</northbc>
        <southbc>40</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Embley, Robert W.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>2030 S Marine Science Dr</address>
          <city>Newport</city>
          <state>OR</state>
          <postal>97365</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>541-867-0275</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>Robert.W.Embley@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Embley, Robert W.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>2030 S Marine Science Dr</address>
          <city>Newport</city>
          <state>OR</state>
          <postal>97365</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>541-867-0275</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>Robert.W.Embley@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20010308</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
