<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>
          <li>Hideji Tanaka, Nancy Navis, Takeshi Onuma, Makoto Yamada, Yuzo Yamamoto, and Sadamasa Tsuchiya of Hokkaido National Fisheries Research Institute</li>
          <li>North Pacific Anadromous Fish Commission (NPAFC)</li>
        </origin>
        <pubdate>20021001</pubdate>
        <title>
          International Salmon Research Aboard the R/V
          <em>Wakatake maru</em>
          in the Central North Pacific Ocean and Bering Sea during the Summer of 2002 (BASIS Japan)
        </title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>
          An annual high-seas salmonid research cruise was conducted in the central North Pacific Ocean and Bering Sea from June 8 to July 21, 2002 onboard the Japanese research vessel,
          <em>Wakatake maru</em>
          , to investigate salmon stock condition. Research cruise activities included collection of data on oceanography, primary production, zooplankton, salmonids, and other organisms. Average sea surface temperatures in the North Pacific were 0.3°C warmer than in 2001, continuing a warming trend begun in 1999. In 2002, superficial warming of the sea surface during the summer produces a shallow seasonal thermocline at 25  to 30 m, which was 10-20 m deeper than previous years. A total of 7931 salmonids was caught by longline and gillnet: 526 fish in the central North Pacific Ocean (St. 3-14) and 7405 fish in the central Bering Sea (St. 15-30). In the North Pacific Ocean, chum salmon was the most abundant  species (58% of the salmonid catch), followed by coho (28%), sockeye (5.7%), steelhead trout (4.8%), pink (2.7%) and chinook salmon (0.6%). In the Bering Sea, chum salmon was the most abundant species (88% of the salmonid catch), followed by sockeye (9.3%), chinook (2.3%), and pink salmon (0.6%). The number of chum salmon caught by longline was three times larger than the previous two years. A total of 718 stomach samples was examined onboard the research vessel. Samples collected from the central North Pacific south of 46ºN showed an unusually high abundance of salps in the stomach contents of chum and coho salmon. In the Bering Sea, the high abundance of euphausiids in the stomach contents of chum, sockeye, pink, and chinook salmon suggests a favorable feeding condition during this cruise. Brain and pituitary samples were obtained from 179 chum salmon for endocrine studies. Along with these samples, olfactory neurone and epithelium were collected from 46 fish to investigate genes related to homing migration. A total of 1042 salmonids (974 chum, 28 sockeye, 21 chinook salmon, 15 coho, 2 pink, and 2 steelhead trout) were released with disk tags to the North Pacific Ocean and Bering Sea. These fish included 48 chum, 18 chinook salmon, 16 sockeye, and 2 steelhead trout, which were released with archival tags.
        </p>
        <p>
          [Reference: Tanaka, H, N. Davis, T. Onuma, M. Yamada, Y. Yamamoto, and S. Tsuchiya. 2002. International salmon research aboard the R/V
          <em>Wakatake maru</em>
          in the central North Pacific Ocean and Bering Sea during the summer of 2002. (NPAFC Doc. 622). 21 p. Hokkaido National Fisheries Research Institute, Fisheries Research Agency, 116 Katsurakoi, Kushiro 085-0802, Japan.]
        </p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>
        <p>
          To summarize the R/V
          <em>Wakatake maru</em>
          cruise research conducted in the central North Pacific Ocean and Bering Sea during June and July 2002.
        </p>
      </purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20020608</begdate>
          <enddate>20020721</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>150</westbc>
        <eastbc>-178</eastbc>
        <northbc>58.5</northbc>
        <southbc>39</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
        <themekey>Plankton</themekey>
        <themekey>Fish</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Sea Temperature</themekey>
        <themekey>Zooplankton</themekey>
        <themekey>Primary Production</themekey>
        <themekey>Salmonids</themekey>
        <themekey>Salmon</themekey>
        <themekey>Salmon Stock Assessment</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Central North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20050225</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>None</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
