<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (OAR), Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory (PMEL)</origin>
        <pubdate>1999</pubdate>
        <title>Hydroacoustic Detection of Volcanic Activity on the Gorda Ridge, February - March 1996</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Beginning at 0700 GMT on 28 February 1996, intense seismicity was detected in the northeast Pacific Ocean using the T-phase Monitoring System developed by
NOAA/PMEL to access the U.S. Navyﾒs SOund SUrveillance System (SOSUS) in the North Pacific. The event was preliminarily located on the northernmost
segment of the Gorda Ridge near 42.67°N and 126.8°W, in the vicinity of the ridge segment high ("narrowgate"). The nature of the seismicity was similar to that
observed in June 1993 at the CoAxial segment of the Juan de Fuca Ridge, which was later documented to be a lateral magma injection with subsequent eruption.
Due to several gaps in the data, the detection information was not as comprehensive as during the CoAxial event, but an initial migration of epicenters from the
narrowgate area down-rift is inferred based on arrival bearings from a single array; there is evidence for an additional diking event on the second and third day of
activity. There is also indication of a concentration of epicenters located near 42.6°N, as occurred during the CoAxial episode at what was later determined to be an
eruption site. Examination of T-wave rise times generally supports this interpretation. Based on the nature and duration of the activity, a response effort was initiated,
which later confirmed hot-water plumes and fresh lava flows at the site. Based on both hydroacoustic information and field observations, it is proposed that the
episode began with a lateral dike injection, possibly with eruptive activity in the summit region, followed by multiple magma pulses and eventual focusing of the
seismic activity and extrusion near 42.6°N.</abstract>
      <purpose />
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-127.5</westbc>
        <eastbc>-126.5</eastbc>
        <northbc>43</northbc>
        <southbc>40.5</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Fox, Christopher G.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>2115 SE OSU Drive</address>
          <city>Newport</city>
          <state>OR</state>
          <postal>97365</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>541-867-0276</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>Christopher.G.Fox@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Fox, Christopher G.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>2115 SE OSU Drive</address>
          <city>Newport</city>
          <state>OR</state>
          <postal>97365</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>541-867-0276</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>Christopher.G.Fox@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20010308</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
