<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), Marshall Space Flight Center</origin>
        <pubdate>19870801-19881130</pubdate>
        <title>SSM/I Pathfinder Sea Ice Concentration from DMSP-F8</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>These sea ice concentrations have been generated by applying the NASA Team algorithm to DMSP F8 SSM/I brightness temperature observations from 19 GHz (vertical and horizontal), 37- and 22 GHz vertical frequencies, calculating two gradients for use as weather filters. Global coverage is provided, but sea ice concentrations are only derived for ocean, ice and possible ice surfaces poleward of 35 degrees latitude, from 1 August 1987 through 30 November 1988.  In the Northern Hemisphere, where data are not filtered due to weather effects, first-year and multi-year concentrations
(in percent) are calculated; total ice concentration is taken as the sum of these two. Only total ice is calculated for the Southern Hemisphere. Twenty-five km swath data are in HDF, available on 8mm tape, 9-track (6250 bpi) tape, or via ftp.   End_Group</abstract>
      <purpose>To report on an ice concentrations have been generated by applying the NASA Team algorithm to DMSP F8 SSM/I brightness temperature observations from 19 GHz (vertical and horizontal), 37- and 22 GHz vertical frequencies, calculating two gradients for use as weather filters.
Group: Reference

Cavalieri, D.J., J. Crawford, M. Drinkwater, W. J. Emery, D. T. Eppler,
L.D. Farmer, M. Goodberlet, R. Jentz, A. Milman, C. Morris, R. Onstott, A.
Schweiger, R. Shuchman, K. Steffen, C. T. Swift, C. Wackerman and R. L.
Weaver. 1992, NASA Sea Ice Validation Program for the Defense
Meteorological Satellite Program Special Sensor Microwave Imager: Final
Report. NASA Technical Memorandum 104559. National Aeronautics and Space
Administration, Washington, D.C. 126 pages. 

Wentz, Frank J. 1992. Final Report Production of SSM/I Data Sets. RSS
Technical Report 090192. Remote Sensing Systems, Santa Rosa, CA. 

End_Group</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19870801</begdate>
          <enddate>19881130</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Ice</themekey>
        <themekey>Sea Ice</themekey>
        <themekey>Hawaii</themekey>
        <themekey>Passive Microwave</themekey>
        <themekey>EOSDIS</themekey>
        <themekey>Sea Ice</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Goodman, Michael</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>977 Explorer Blvd.</address>
          <city>Hunstville</city>
          <state>AL</state>
          <postal>35806</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>205-922-5813</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>michael.goodman@msfc.nasa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Goodman, Michael</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>977 Explorer Blvd.</address>
          <city>Hunstville</city>
          <state>AL</state>
          <postal>35806</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>205-922-5813</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>michael.goodman@msfc.nasa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19980729</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
