<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>North Pacific Andromous Fish Commission (NPAFC)</origin>
        <pubdate>20030301</pubdate>
        <title>Annual Report of the Bering-Aleutian Salmon International Survey (BASIS), 2002</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>The Bering-Aleutian Salmon International Survey (BASIS) is a North Pacific Anadromous Fish Commission (NPAFC)-coordinated program of cooperative research in the Bering Sea that was developed to clarify the mechanisms of biological response by salmon to the conditions caused by climate changes. In 2002, for the first time scientists of all NPAFC member nations (Canada, Japan, Russia, and the United States) cooperated in the design and execution of a complex field survey of salmon across the entire Bering Sea. Vast amounts of data on biology and ecology of foraging salmon and other nekton species were collected during this survey. Oceanographic and other environmental data were collected simultaneously with fishing operations. Six research vessels sampled all major geographic regions, marine habitats (coastal, shelf, basin), and life history stages of salmon during summer and fall (July-November) 2002. A variety of fishing gear (trawl, gillnet, and longline) and plankton sampling gear were used. Calibration experiments were conducted to evaluate differences in some vessel/gear combinations. Samples and data for salmon age, growth, food habits, lipid content, bioenergetics, stock identification (genetic samples, scale and otolith collections, tags), and parasite research were collected. Salmon were tagged and released with external disk tags to supplement historical data on known ranges of Asian and North American stocks in the Bering Sea. Some fish were tagged with archival and data-storage tags that measure water temperature, swimming depth, and swimming speed. This report summarizes only those results available to the NPAFC BASIS Working Group by May 2003.</p>
        <p>[Reference: North Pacific Anadromous Fish Commission. 2003. Annual Report of the Bering- Aleutian Salmon International Survey (BASIS), 2002. (NPAFC Doc. 684.) 38p. Vancouver, B.C., Canada.]</p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>
        <p>To report on the annual Bering-Aleutian Salmon International Survey (BASIS) of 2002</p>
      </purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20020701</begdate>
          <enddate>20021130</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>150</westbc>
        <eastbc>-157</eastbc>
        <northbc>65.5</northbc>
        <southbc>39</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Fish</themekey>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
        <themekey>Plankton</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Salmon</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Aleutian Islands</themekey>
        <themekey>Zooplankton</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20050225</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>None</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
