<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), Alaska Fisheries Science Center (AFSC)</origin>
        <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
        <title>AFSC Marine Salmon Interactions Monitoring Data Sets: Auke Creek</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The Auke Lake system has natural populations of pink, chum, sockeye and coho salmon, and supports populations of Dolly Varden, and cutthroat and steelhead trout.  Chinook salmon have returned to Auke Creek since 1986 as a result of off-site releases of juveniles from other hatcheries. The National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), and its predecessor agency, the U.S. Bureau of Commercial Fisheries, began salmon research at Auke Creek in 1961. Several fish counting weirs were installed in Auke Creek to capture salmon adults during the early 1960s. In 1965, a permanent, low-height weir was constructed and was used until 1980, when a modern, two-way weir was built. Weir counts of sockeye salmon adults at Auke Creek began in 1963; other species were included after 1966. Sockeye smolts were counted in some years between 1963 and 1980, and other downstream migrants were counted after 1969.</abstract>
      <purpose>To document  the species composition, abundance, and timing of potential prey organisms as food for pink and chum salmon fry first entering nearshore marine waters.  This early marine residency of salmon fry is crucial in determining survival to adult and year-class strength.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19630101</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>In Progress</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-134.64</westbc>
        <eastbc>-134.64</eastbc>
        <northbc>58.37967</northbc>
        <southbc>58.37967</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Fish</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Salmon</themekey>
        <themekey>Auke Creek, Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Contact Source.</accconst>
    <useconst>Contact Source.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Heard, William R.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>11305 Glacier Highway</address>
          <city>Juneau</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99801-8626</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-789-6003</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>bill.heard@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Heard, William R.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>11305 Glacier Highway</address>
          <city>Juneau</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99801-8626</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-789-6003</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>bill.heard@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20041027</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Contact Source.</metac>
    <metuc>Contact Source.</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
