<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (OAR), Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory (PMEL)</origin>
        <pubdate>19871231</pubdate>
        <title>Northward flow in the Bering and Chukchi Seas</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The ocean circulation on the Bering and Chukchi sea shelves is investigated using a barotropic numerical model. In the presence of the winter seasonal wind stress from the northeast, observed northward transport through Bering Strait of 0.6 Sv for the 8-month winter season 1981-1982 can be driven by a sea level difference of 0.4 m between the Pacific and Arctic oceans. This sea level difference between basins is in agreement with hydrographic estimates.  In the absence of wind stress a 0.4-m sea level difference drives a northward transport through Bering Strait of 1.1 Sv. Maximum transport through Bering Strait is geostrophically limited, not frictionally or inertially limited. Major qualitative circulation features of the region are evident in the simulations. Westward intensification of the northward transport across the Bering Sea shelf is confirmed, with the major transport occurring in the relatively deep Gulf of Anadyr. In the absence of wind, Anadyr Strait contributes 72% of the northward transport through Bering Strait. With northeasterly winds there is a net clockwise circulation around Saint Lawrence Island. Within the 20-m isobath, North and Kotzebue sounds are little influenced by the general circulation. Northward transport in the Chukchi Sea bifurcates in the vicinity of Point Hope. The predominant branch is directed toward the northwest in a broad canyon
feature south of Heralds Shoal, and the balance becomes the Alaskan Coastal Current between Cape Lisburne and Point Barrow.</abstract>
      <purpose>To record the northward flow in the Bering and Chukchi Seas</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19871231</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Chukchi Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Flow Trajectory</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Overland, James E.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6795</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>James.E.Overland@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Overland, James E.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6795</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>James.E.Overland@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990203</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
