<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), Alaska Fisheries Science Center (AFSC)</origin>
        <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
        <title>Photogrammetry of Harbor Seals at Glacial Ice Haul-out Sites</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>In August 2001, photogrammetric surveys were conducted at glacial haul-out sites in the Gulf of Alaska, in conjunction with aerial surveys of terrestrial sites in that region.  In August 2002, similar surveys were conducted at glacial haul-out sites in Southeast Alaska, again in conjunction with aerial surveys of terrestrial sites in that region.  Together, the 2001 and 2002 photogrammetric surveys encompassed all the known glacial haul-out sites in Alaska (with the exception of a few small haul-out sites that were surveyed successfully using traditional aerial survey techniques).</p>
        <p>From May to August 2002, monthly photogrammetric surveys were conducted at Disenchantment and Icy Bays, in conjunction with studies of the potential impact of cruise-ship traffic on the behavior and life history of harbor seals at glacial haul-out sites.  In addition, a comparative study was conducted in June 2002 during which large-format color photographs and infrared images were collected simultaneously.  The data from this comparative study will be used to evaluate the utility of thermal/infrared survey techniques versus the color photography used for all our recent photogrammetric surveys (i.e., those described above).</p>
        <p>AFSC Quarterly Report: Jul. - Sep. 2002</p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>Standard aerial survey techniques are not effective for estimating the number of seals hauled out on ice floes dispersed throughout glacial fjords.  It is estimated that as much as 20% of the Gulf of Alaska harbor seal stock may be using glacial ice habitats at various times of the year.  Following a   possible 80%- 85% decrease in the size of the Gulf of Alaska harbor seal population since 1970, there is a pressing need to accurately assess the abundance of harbor seals in glacial ice habitats.  The Polar Ecosystem Program is currently developing methods for accurately counting seals inhabiting the ice fields of tidewater glaciers.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20020501</begdate>
          <enddate>20020831</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-145</westbc>
        <eastbc>-130</eastbc>
        <northbc>60.17</northbc>
        <southbc>50</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Mammals</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Seals</themekey>
        <themekey>Glacial Ice Haul-Out Sites</themekey>
        <themekey>Southeast Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Disenchantment Bay</themekey>
        <themekey>Icy Bay</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>Contact the agency</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Simpkins, Michael A.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4037</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6615</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Mike.Simpkins@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Simpkins, Michael A.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4037</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6615</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Mike.Simpkins@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20030521</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>Contact the agency</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
