<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Moss Landing Marine Laboratories</origin>
        <pubdate>2002</pubdate>
        <title>Age and Growth and Radiometric Validation of a Deep-sea, Habitat-forming Gorgonian (Primnoa resedaeformis) from the Gulf of Alaska</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Sustainable fisheries require 1) viable stock populations with appropriate harvest limits and 2) appropriate habitat for the fisheries to survive, forage, seek refuge, grow and reproduce.  Unlike some deep-water rocky habitats, those formed from deep-water stands of coral may be vulnerable to fishing disturbance and therefore affect on the fishery may be confounded by simultaneous loss of habitat during fishing effort.  Thus, the rate at which habitat can be restored is a critical aspect of fishery management.  The purpose of this study was to characterize growth rates for a habitat-forming deep-sea coral.  Two nearly complete colonies of red tree coral (Primnoa resedaeformis) collected from off southeast Alaska were used for an analysis of age and growth characteristics.  CAT scans revealed that colonies consisted of multiple settlement events, where older basal structures provide for settlement of new colonies.  The decay of exogenous 210Pb over the length of the colony was used to validate age estimates from growth zone counts.  Age estimates were over 100 yr for sections near the heavily calcified base.  Based on validated growth zone counts, growth of red tree coral ranged from 1.60 to 2.32 cm per year in height and was approximately 0.36 mm per year in diameter.  These growth rates suggest that the fishery habitat created by red tree coral is extremely vulnerable to bottom fishing activities and may take over 100 years to recover.  

 [ Co-PIs: Gregor M. Cailliet, Allen H. Andrews ]  [ An NPMR project ]

[ Reference: Andrews, A.H., Cordes, E., Mahoney, M.M., Munk, K., Coale, K.H., Cailliet, G.M., and Heifetz, J. 2002. Age and growth and radiometric age validation of a deep-sea, habitat-forming gorgonian (Primnoa resedaeformis) from the Gulf of Alaska. In: Biology of cold water corals. Eds: L. Watling and M. Risk. Special issue of Hydrobiologia. 471:101-110. ]</abstract>
      <purpose>A proposal to "determine the age and growth of two deep-sea, habitat forming octocorallian corals of the Gulf of Alaska and Bering Sea, with radiometric age validation and climate correlation" to NPMR.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19990701</begdate>
          <enddate>20000731</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>167</westbc>
        <eastbc>-163</eastbc>
        <northbc>67</northbc>
        <southbc>53</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Biology</themekey>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Essential Fish Habitat (EFH)</themekey>
        <themekey>Biogenic Habitat</themekey>
        <themekey>Primnoa Resedaeformis</themekey>
        <themekey>Gorgonian</themekey>
        <themekey>Deep-sea Coral</themekey>
        <themekey>Radiometric Age</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Gulf of Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Unknown</accconst>
    <useconst>Unknown</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Cailliet, Gregor M.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>8272 Moss Landing Road</address>
          <city>Moss Landing</city>
          <state>CA</state>
          <postal>95039-9647</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>831-771-4432</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>831-771-4403</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cailliet@mlml.calstate.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Cailliet, Gregor M.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>8272 Moss Landing Road</address>
          <city>Moss Landing</city>
          <state>CA</state>
          <postal>95039-9647</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>831-771-4432</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>831-771-4403</cntfax>
        <cntemail>cailliet@mlml.calstate.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20000202</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Unknown</metac>
    <metuc>Unknown</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
