<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>
          <li>Edward V. Farley, Jr., Bruce Wing, Angela Middleton, John Pohl, and Lee Hulbert of Auke Bay Laboratory, Alaska Fisheries Science Center, NMFS, Juneau, AK, USA</li>
          <li>Jamal Moss of the School of Aquatic and Fisheries Sciences, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA</li>
          <li>Marc Trudel of Pacific Biological Station, Nanaimo, British Columbia, Canada</li>
          <li>Edward Parks and Ted Hamilton of Yukon River Drainage Fisheries Association, Anchorage, AK, USA</li>
          <li>Cynthia Lagoudakis of the U.S. Forest Service, Juneau, AK, USA</li>
          <li>Danielle McCallum of NWO, Inc. Edmonds, WA, USA</li>
          <li>North Pacific Anadromous Fish Commission</li>
        </origin>
        <pubdate>20030501</pubdate>
        <title>Midwater Rope Trawl Oceanographic Data Collected from the Eastern Bering Sea During Fall 2002</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>As part of the Bering-Aleutian Salmon International Survey (BASIS) effort to survey the Bering Sea, the National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), Ocean Carrying Capacity (OCC) program conducted a fall survey on the eastern Bering Sea shelf to provide key ecological data for the eastern Bering Sea salmon stocks during their juvenile life-history stage.</p>
        <p>
          The survey was conducted aboard the contracted fishing vessel (F/V)
          <em>Sea Storm</em>
          .  Oceanographic data were collected at each trawl station immediately prior to each trawl haul. Profiles of salinity and temperature from surface to near bottom depths were collected using a Sea-Bird SBE 19 Seacat profiler. Plankton samples were collected using 60-cm diameter bongo samplers fitted with 505- and 333-μm mesh nets. The bongo nets were towed obliquely from near surface to approximately 10 m from the bottom; the estimated depth of each bongo tow was calculated by wire angle and length of wire. The volume of water filtered by each net was estimated by flow meters, and the plankton samples were preserved in 10% formalin.
        </p>
        <p>[Reference: Farley, E.V., Jr., B. Wing, A. Middleton, J. Pohl, L. Hulbert, J. Moss, M. Trudel, E. Parks, T. Hamilton, C. Lagoudakis, and D. McCallum. 2003. Eastern Bering Sea (BASIS) coastal research (August - October 2002) on juvenile salmon. (NPAFC Doc. 678.) 25p. Auke Bay Laboratory, Alaska Fisheries Science Center, NMFS, NOAA, 11305 Glacier Highway, Juneau, AK 99801-8626.]  This cruise report is available for download at http://www.npafc.org/restricted_doc/2003%20Documents_PDF/678(usa).pdf.</p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>
        <p>To understand mechanisms underlying the effects of environment on distribution, migration, and growth of juvenile salmon on the eastern Bering Sea shelf.</p>
      </purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20020820</begdate>
          <enddate>20021011</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>172.5</westbc>
        <eastbc>-161</eastbc>
        <northbc>65</northbc>
        <southbc>54.5</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
        <themekey>Plankton</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Sea Salinity</themekey>
        <themekey>Sea Temperature</themekey>
        <themekey>Trawl</themekey>
        <themekey>Eastern Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>Contact Source.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20050225</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>Contact Source.</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
