<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (OAR), Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory (PMEL)</origin>
        <pubdate>1994</pubdate>
        <title>Gradients in the Composition of Hydrothermal Fluids from the Endeavour Segment Vent Field: Phase Separation and Brine Loss</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Hydrothermal fluid samples collected in 1984, 1987, and 1988 from a large vent field near 47°57N on the Endeavour segment of the Juan de Fuca Ridge (JFR)
have been analyzed for major and minor elements and gases. There are of the order of 100 individual smoker vents on ~10 large sulfide structures, which are
localized along faults and fault intersections across the vent field. Each sulfide structure has a characteristic fluid composition, which varies very little from one vent
orifice to the next, or from year to year, on a given structure. However, there are large gradients in fluid composition across the vent field, with endmember chlorinity
increasing from ~255 mmol/kg in the SW to 505 mmol/kg in the NE. End-member concentrations of major elements are well correlated with chlorinity, and
endmember volatile concentrations in the lowest chlorinity fluids are approximately twice as high as in the highest chlorinity fluids. The gradients in composition
across the vent field and measured vent fluid temperatures &gt;400°C are consistent with supercritical phase separation and loss of brine phase below the seafloor. The
factor-of-2 variation in CO (and HS) is larger than expected for loss of a very high-chlorinity brine. Concentrations of iron and manganese are not positively
correlated with chlorinity, suggesting that temperature and pH are more important in controlling metal solubility. Elevated ammonia and bromide/chloride ratios
indicate that there has been subseafloor interaction between the hydrothermal fluids and organic matter, and high boron concentrations point to a sedimentary
source.</abstract>
      <purpose />
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-128</westbc>
        <eastbc>-127</eastbc>
        <northbc>48</northbc>
        <southbc>47</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Butterfield, David A.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6722</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>David.A.Butterfield@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Butterfield, David A.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6722</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>David.A.Butterfield@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20010307</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
