<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (OAR), Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory (PMEL)</origin>
        <pubdate>1994</pubdate>
        <title>Introduction to Special Section on Volcanic and Hydrothermal Processes on the Southern Juan de Fuca Ridge</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>In September 1986, during an investigation of the thermal and chemical properties of the water column overlying the southern Juan de Fuca Ridge (JdFR), a plume
of hydrothermal effluent of extraordinary size and heat content was discovered [Baker et al., 1987]. The center of this "megaplume" (and a subsequent one found in
1987) was several hundred meters shallower than the "steady state" hydrothermal plume observed over the ridge and contained the equivalent of about 1 year's
discharge from a typical ridge crest vent field [Baker et al., 1989]. A conductivity- temperature-depth (CTD) profile taken 1 month later at the site revealed that the
megaplume was no longer present. Modeling of the dynamics of megaplume generation revealed that it was consistent with a sudden expulsion of fluids from a
preexisting hydrothermal system, probably from a fissure produced during an episode of seafloor extension [Baker et al., 1989]. Independent evidence for this
interpretation was discovered when subsequent surveys of the northern Cleft segment using Sea Beam, side scan sonar and deeply towed camera revealed that a
basaltic fissure eruption had occurred in the area between 1983 and 1987 [Chadwick et al., 1991; Embley et al., 1991; Fox et al., 1992]. The discovery of the
megaplume focused a broad research effort within the source area on the northern portion of the Cleft segment (Figure 1). This special issue is an outgrowth of a
special session at the Fall 1991 AGU Meeting and includes results of several years of interdisciplinary field investigations focused on this area.</abstract>
      <purpose />
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-128</westbc>
        <eastbc>-123</eastbc>
        <northbc>44</northbc>
        <southbc>39</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Embley, Robert W.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>2030 S Marine Science Dr</address>
          <city>Newport</city>
          <state>OR</state>
          <postal>97365</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>541-867-0275</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>Robert.W.Embley@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Embley, Robert W.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>2030 S Marine Science Dr</address>
          <city>Newport</city>
          <state>OR</state>
          <postal>97365</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>541-867-0275</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>Robert.W.Embley@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20010308</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
