<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Department of Civil and Structural Engineering</origin>
        <pubdate>19970702</pubdate>
        <title>Surface Ozone Pattern in Hong Kong</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Surface ozone (O3) and its precursors in rural and urban areas of Hong
     Kong are analyzed through the seasonal, temporal, and spatial variation
     patterns. The seasonal O3 shows a unique pattern with a major peak in
     autumn and a trough in summer. The spring and winter seasons are the
     transition periods with a relatively small peak in spring. The seasonal
     alternation of the prevailing oceanic and continental air masses, plus the
     climate system associated with the Asian monsoon system, are the governing
     factors for the temporal O3 pattern in Hong Kong. The O3 imported by these
     air masses is found to be the dominating factor for the fluctuation of ambient
     O3 in Hong Kong. The aged air masses associated with the continental
     outflow from China carry with them anthropogenic air pollutants emitted from
     the blooming industrial and urban neighborhoods north of Hong Kong in
     Guangdong Province, China. Under favorable meteorological conditions for
     photochemical O3 formation in southeast China, the O3 level reaches a
     maximum in autumn. The absence of a local urban or a summer O3 peak
     suggests that the local O3 formation is not the dominant source of O3 in
     summer. The absence of an elevated ground-level O3 peak in the spring
     season is an indication that the stratospheric intrusion process of O3 is not a
     significant source of surface O3 in Hong Kong. The authorsﾒ analysis also
     shows that the emission of O3 precursors from motor vehicles and the
     complex topography within the territories has a local effect on the spatial O3
     distribution and diurnal O3 pattern in Hong Kong.</abstract>
      <purpose>To report on the Surface Ozone Pattern in Hong Kong</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19970702</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>China</themekey>
        <themekey>Holocene Erosion</themekey>
        <themekey>Arctic</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Oxygen</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Chan, L. Y.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Hong Kong Polytechnic University</address>
          <city>Kowloon</city>
          <state>Hong Kong</state>
          <postal />
          <country>China</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Chan, L. Y.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Hong Kong Polytechnic University</address>
          <city>Kowloon</city>
          <state>Hong Kong</state>
          <postal />
          <country>China</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990205</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
