<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (OAR), Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory (PMEL)</origin>
        <pubdate>1987</pubdate>
        <title>Coastal Winds of the Southeast Alaska Peninsula</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Hourly measurements of wind speed and wind direction from Cherni Island, Thin Point, Cold Bay, and Ugaiushak Island during the latter half of 1984 and the first half of 1985 show evidence of orographic steering of winds in the coastal zone. Surface wind directions at Cherni Island, Thin Point, and Cold Bay often were attributable--30% of the time at Cherni Island and Thin Point, 50% of the time at Cold Bay--to channeling of the wind by a gap in the Aleutian Range. At Ugaiushak Island 30% of surface winds came from the WNW. It is likely that these winds followed a convoluted path through the mountains from the Meshik River valley to the southwest. Representations of topographically undisturbed surface winds for the same four locations over the period June 1984 through May 1985 were produced by turning and reducing gradient winds computed from digitized, 6-hourly, sea-level-pressure analyses obtained from the U.S. Navy's Fleet Numerical Oceanography Center. These wind estimates show a more evenly distributed wind direction population, with a slight tendency for winds to dominate from the NW and SE. Monthly correlation coefficients between measured and estimated u and v wind components ranged from 0.48 to 0.94. Because of anomalous winter and spring weather conditions, measured Cold Bay wind statistics for some months of the study do not compare favorably with climate averages. Yearly averages compare more favorably, and these statistics may be representative of normal conditions.</abstract>
      <purpose />
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-168</westbc>
        <eastbc>-152</eastbc>
        <northbc>58</northbc>
        <southbc>53</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Macklin, S. Allen</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6798</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>S.Allen.Macklin@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Macklin, S. Allen</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6798</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>S.Allen.Macklin@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20010306</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
