<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Fisheries and Oceans Canada - Ocean Science And Productivity, Pacific</origin>
        <pubdate>Unpublished material</pubdate>
        <title>Line P (PERD Project) - Oceanic carbon dioxide, 1988-present</title>
        <othercit>Publications: Wong, C.S.;Bellegay, R.D.;Smith, G.E.;Page, J.S.;Chan Y.H. 1985. Seasonal changes in PC02 in surface Pacific Ocean. In Proceedings, International Conference on Atmospheric Carbon Dioxide at Kandersteg (Switzerland), 2-6 September 1985, pp. 189-196.</othercit>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Observations of large-scale changes in oceanic PC02 and supporting data of oceanographic properties and carbonate chemistry. May also include other lines and other projects (Line Z, Line R, Line PE, JGOFS, WOCE, Seamounts, Alaskan Gyre, Eddy, ).</abstract>
      <purpose>Determination of the penetration of CO2 into the water column.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Risk Justification: Custodian will be leaving soon and has a large quantity of data not secured in a regional data centre.
Risk of Loss: High
Impact Justification: Long term time series (more than 10 years)
Impact of Loss: High
Recommended Action: Obtain access to data and bring to archives
Additional Info: Freon data have been partly published; data will be made available after publication. PCO2 data (1973-1999) have been sent to the OSAP archive. Much of the productivity and chlorophyll data have been published, will be made available. DOC data are in press, and will be made available. DON data have been written up into a paper which has not yet been submitted for publication. TCO2 and Talkalinity profiles have been made available (1972-1997) and TCO2 and Talkalinity surface data (1972-1990) have been made available. C13 and O-18 data are custody of C.S. Wong.
Storage Requirements: 50MB+unknown</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>1988</begdate>
          <enddate>present</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>In work</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>145</westbc>
        <eastbc>125.5</eastbc>
        <northbc>50</northbc>
        <southbc>48.5</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>NASA/GCMD Earth Science Keywords</themekt>
        <themekey>Earth Science</themekey>
        <themekey>Oceans</themekey>
        <themekey>Ocean Chemistry</themekey>
        <themekey>Carbon Dioxide</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>biota</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>DFO Areas</placekt>
        <placekey>North Pacific Ocean</placekey>
        <placekey>South Outer Coast (West Coast VI)</placekey>
        <placekey>South Inner Coast (Johnstone, Georgia, JDF, inlets and passages)</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>May Be Private</accconst>
    <useconst>Temperature, salinity, dissolved oxygen, and nutrient data are stored on the OSAP database, Departmentally accessible. Other data will be available after publication/quality checked (see Additional Information, below)</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>C.S. Wong</cntper>
          <cntorg>Ocean Science and Productivity</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Institute of Ocean Sciences, P.O. Box 6000, 9860 West Saanich Road</address>
          <city>Sidney</city>
          <state>British Columbia</state>
          <postal>V8L 4B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(250)363-6407</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>(250) 363-6476</cntfax>
        <cntemail>wongcs@pac.dfo-mpo.gc.ca</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>Standardization of chemical instrumentation with known or commercially prepared standards.</logic>
    <complete>Dataset Complications: Some DOC data are questionable.
 Meteorological data from NOAA buoy at Station P no longer freely available. Portable met. station on ship gives apparent measures of wind speed and direction for PCO2, must be corrected for ship`s heading, speed, etc.
PCO2 originally measured by IR spectrophotometer, then by gas chromatograph, now using a non-dispersive IR analyzer.
C13 and O-18 data are custody of C.S. Wong.
Electronic Data Complications: Temperature, salinity, oxygen and nutrient data on IOS archived database are not quite conforming to IOS Header format, and are therefore difficult to search. All of the magtapes are older than their guaranteed physical lifespan. The last attempt to retrieve data from a magtape was successful (July 7, 2000).</complete>
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Unknown</procdesc>
        <procdate>Unknown</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>John Page</cntper>
          <cntorg>Ocean Science and Productivity</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Institute of Ocean Sciences, P.O. Box 6000, 9860 West Saanich Road</address>
          <city>Sidney</city>
          <state>British Columbia</state>
          <postal>V8L 4B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(250)363-6467</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>(250) 363-6746</cntfax>
        <cntemail>pagej@pac.dfo-mpo.gc.ca</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>PAC-OSAP-004-7039</resdesc>
    <distliab>[unknown]</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <nondig>Hardcopy Original Exists: Y
Hardcopy Locations: Joseph Linguanti, Rm 1246, IOS
Hardcopy Description: Various log books, cruise reports, and data sheets from Line P cruises, data sheets from individual analyses. Includes the weathership meteorological data.
Hardcopy Volume: 3 full file drawers
Physical Sample Exists: Y
Physical Sample Locations: C.S. Wong, Coolers, IOS Hangar Bldg.
Physical Sample Volume: C-13: about 2600; O-18: unknown number
Physical Sample Description: C-13 in seawater and O-18 in seawater in glass bottles.
Physical Sample Complications: Samples need to be kept refrigerated.</nondig>
      <fees>Ask Custodian</fees>
      <ordering>Contact data custodian. For data on the OSAP database, contact Joseph Linguanti, IOS, linguantij@pac.dfo-mpo.gc.ca</ordering>
    </stdorder>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>Spreadsheets, ASCII files, IOS Header files</formname>
          <formcont>for files in IOS archives: IOS header and IOSLIB libraries.</formcont>
          <transize>99.9</transize>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <offoptn>
            <offmedia>VMS network hard drives; computer hard drives, PC network hard drives, zip drives, travan tape,</offmedia>
            <recfmt>unknown</recfmt>
          </offoptn>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>Ask Custodian</fees>
      <ordering>Electronic Data Doc Locations: Header information in each file.
Dataset Locations: DATA_LIBRARY: (data in IOS archives); other data custody of C.S. Wong</ordering>
    </stdorder>
    <techpreq>Backup by Custodian: Y
Backup by Automation: Y
Backup Description: IOS archived data: VMS backup on DLT tapes. Most data are on Alpha/Unix boxes. Magtape (9-track) ascii data files always saved to 3 miror image tapes. VAX account backup saved to only 1 tape. Most data on tapes are no longer current version. Some magtapes were sent to Vancouver tape archive some years ago.</techpreq>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20080211</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Fisheries and Oceans Canada
Canadian Hydrographic Service</cntorg>
          <cntper>Chelsea Stanley and Matt McCormick</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
          <address>Institute of Ocean Sciences
P.O. Box 6000
9860 West Saanich Road</address>
          <city>Sidney</city>
          <state>British Columbia</state>
          <postal>V8L 4B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>(250) 363-6358</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>(250) 363-6823</cntfax>
        <cntemail>ChartSales@pac.dfo-mpo.gc.ca</cntemail>
        <hours>M-F, 08:30-16:30 Pacific Time</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-1998-1</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
