<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>California Academy of Sciences (CAS), Department of Ichthyology</origin>
        <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
        <title>CAS Ichthyology Primary Types Imagebase</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>Ichthyology Primary Types Imagebase database contains three categories of images: color photographs, radiographs, and original illustrations. In the case of syntypes, a single specimen is selected to represent the syntypic series. This is true even when the series is distributed in several discreet lots. The selection is based primarily on appearance for photography, so these may not be the best specimens for taxonomic purposes, and in some cases, may only represent one of two or more taxa actually present in the series. The project is essentially complete, although new images will be posted as old types are returned and new types are deposited here.</p>
        <p>Direct any questions, comments, or corrections to David Catania (dcatania@calacademy.org), Sr. Collection Manager, Dept. of Ichthyology.</p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>
        <p>The California Academy of Sciences Department of Ichthyology type collection contains over 37,000 specimens in over 6,000 lots, of which more than 1,600 are primary type lots. These were the focus of an imaging project funded by the National Science Foundation (NSF DBI-9876822). The type database consists of names that were published using CAS, Stanford University (SU), or Indiana University (IU) specimens as primary types (holotype, syntype, lectotype, or neotype). Most of the Indiana collection was acquired by the Academy in 1928, although part of the collection, including some types, were given to the Carnegie Museum and later transferred to the Field Museum of Natural History. The entire Stanford collection came to the Academy in 1970. Some images are lacking because the type specimen cannot be found, has been transferred to another institution (deaccessioned), or is currently on loan.</p>
      </purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>In Progress</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>0</westbc>
        <eastbc>0</eastbc>
        <northbc>0</northbc>
        <southbc>0</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Fish</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Ichthyology</themekey>
        <themekey>Zoology</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Review http://www.calacademy.org/research/ichthyology/Types/about_types.html#Use</accconst>
    <useconst>Review http://www.calacademy.org/research/ichthyology/Types/about_types.html#Use</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Eschmeyer, William</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing Address</addrtype>
          <address>875 Howard St.</address>
          <city>San Francisco</city>
          <state>CA</state>
          <postal>94103</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>415-321-8284</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>415-321-8643</cntfax>
        <cntemail>weschmeyer@calacademy.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Eschmeyer, William</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing Address</addrtype>
          <address>875 Howard St.</address>
          <city>San Francisco</city>
          <state>CA</state>
          <postal>94103</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>415-321-8284</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>415-321-8643</cntfax>
        <cntemail>weschmeyer@calacademy.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20051205</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Review http://www.calacademy.org/research/ichthyology/Types/about_types.html#Use</metac>
    <metuc>Review http://www.calacademy.org/research/ichthyology/Types/about_types.html#Use</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
