<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Resource Assessment and Conservation Engineering Division  (RACE), Alaska Fisheries Science Center (AFSC), National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA)</origin>
        <pubdate>20040401</pubdate>
        <title>Data Report: 2002 Aleutian Islands Bottom Trawl Survey</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Eighth in a series dating from 1980, the second biennial groundfish assessment survey of the Aleutian Islands region was conducted during the summer of 2002 by the Alaska Fisheries Science Center's (AFSC) Resource Assessment and Conservation Engineering (RACE) Division.  The survey area covered the continental shelf and upper continental slope to 500 m in the Aleutian Archipelago from Islands of Four Mountains (170째 W long.) to Stalemate Bank (170째 E long.), including Petrel Bank and Petrel Spur (180째 long.), and the northern side of the Aleutian Islands between Unimak Pass (165째 W long.) and Islands of Four Mountains.  The survey was conducted aboard three chartered trawlers, the FV Morning Star, FV Sea Storm, and FV Vesteraalen.  Samples were collected successfully at 417 survey stations using standard RACE Division Poly Nor'Eastern high-opening bottom trawl nets with rubber bobbin roller gear.  The primary survey objectives were to define the distribution and estimate the relative abundance of principal groundfish and commercially or ecologically important invertebrate species that inhabit the Aleutian marine habitat and to collect data to define biological parameters useful to fisheries researchers and managers such as growth rates; length-weight relationships; feeding habits; and size, sex, and age compositions.</abstract>
      <purpose>Annual survey data report.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20020501</begdate>
          <enddate>20020701</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Other</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>170</westbc>
        <eastbc>-165</eastbc>
        <northbc>53</northbc>
        <southbc>51</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Fish</themekey>
        <themekey>Management</themekey>
        <themekey>Benthic</themekey>
        <themekey>Biology</themekey>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Aleutian Islands</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Zenger, Jr., Harold H.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4158</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6723</cntfax>
        <cntemail>harold.zenger@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Zenger, Jr., Harold H.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4158</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6723</cntfax>
        <cntemail>harold.zenger@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20040803</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>None</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
