<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>
          Meghan Cronin, Chris Meinig, and Chris Sabine
          <br />
          National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (OAR), Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory (PMEL)
        </origin>
        <pubdate>20040616</pubdate>
        <title>Real-Time Data from the Kuroshio Extension Observatory (KEO) Mooring (PMEL)</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>In June 2004, a surface buoy was deployed in the Kuroshio Extension recirculation gyre, at 144.5ºE, 32.3ºN. The Kuroshio Extension Observatory (KEO) mooring carries a suite of meteorological sensors to measure winds, air temperature, relative humidity, rainfall, and solar and longwave radiation. With measurements of sea surface temperature and these surface meteorological measurements, the net air-sea heat, moisture and momentum fluxes can be computed. Surface and subsurface instrumentation includes temperature and salinity at 1 m to 500 m. Daily-averaged data are available in near-realtime at http://www.pmel.noaa.gov/keo/data.html. In June 2005, a pCO2 sensor will be included for computation of the air-sea CO2 flux. In the future, additional sensors may be added to the mooring.</p>
        <p>KEO is one of NOAA's most recent contributions to the global network of time series stations. The network, now referred to as OCEAN Sustained Interdisciplinary Timeseries Environment observation System (OceanSITES; http://www.oceansites.org/OceanSITES/), provides data for the science community, policy makers, and society in order to detect global climate and ecosystem changes, to describe/quantify them, to understand/explain them and to develop a capability to predict them.</p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>To contribute to the global network of time series reference sites.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20040616</begdate>
          <enddate>20051109</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>In Progress</progress>
      <update>Daily</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>144</westbc>
        <eastbc>144</eastbc>
        <northbc>32.3</northbc>
        <southbc>32.3</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
        <themekey>Atmosphere</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Mooring</themekey>
        <themekey>Atmospheric Pressure</themekey>
        <themekey>Radiation</themekey>
        <themekey>Rain</themekey>
        <themekey>Wind</themekey>
        <themekey>Sea Temperature</themekey>
        <themekey>Kuroshio Region</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Cronin, Meghan</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6449</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6744</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Meghan.F.Cronin@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Cronin, Meghan</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6449</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6744</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Meghan.F.Cronin@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20050321</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>None</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
