<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Hadley Centre for Climate Prediction and Research, Meteorological Office</origin>
        <pubdate>19970528</pubdate>
        <title>Assessing Potential Seasonal Predictability with an  Ensemble of Multidecadal GCM Simulations</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>A global search for areas where seasonal prediction may be feasible has
     attracted scientific interest for many years. This contribution is based primarily on
     data from a six-member ensemble of 45-yr climate runs, each of which is forced
     by observed sea surface temperatures (SSTs) and sea-ice extents and are unique
     only in their initial atmospheric conditions. The potentially predictable component
     of atmospheric interannual variability is assumed to be that due to oceanic forcing,
     and using ﾓanalysis of variance,ﾔ this is separated from the unpredictable internal
     component; potential predictability is measured as the ratio of ocean-forced
     variance to total variance. Significance levels and confidence intervals are
     calculated, both of which are essential for a meaningful interpretation of
     predictability estimates; the latter show there is low susceptibility to sampling
     problems here because of the large data source available.

       Global maps of potential predictability, for simulated seasonal mean
     precipitation and mean sea level pressure (MSLP), are shown for both the
     solstitial and equinoctial seasons. In most regions, this model-based predictability
     estimate has large variations through the annual cycle. Not surprisingly, the highest
     predictability occurs over the tropical oceans, particularly the Atlantic and Pacific,
     for which a better knowledge of the influence of SSTs on diabatic heating is
     important for understanding the variability of teleconnected regions. Land areas
     displaying high predictability tend to support existing empirical studies, although
     over Australia and parts of Africa the modelﾒs response to SSTs seems
     erroneously weak. In the midlatitude Northern Hemisphere, a winterﾖspring peak
     of predictability is confirmed, but a notable autumnal minimal of predictability is
     also proposed. At polar latitudes, there is a small but significant influence of SSTs
     on spring MSLP, and in some localities a moderate influence on precipitation.
     Further work is required with observational data to properly assess these findings.</abstract>
      <purpose>A report on assessing Potential Seasonal Predictability with an  Ensemble of Multidecadal GCM Simulations</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19970528</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Meteorology</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Rowell, David P.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Hadley Centre</address>
          <city>Bracknell</city>
          <state />
          <postal />
          <country>United Kingdom</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Rowell, David P.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Hadley Centre</address>
          <city>Bracknell</city>
          <state />
          <postal />
          <country>United Kingdom</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990204</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
