<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Environmental Satellite, Data and Information Service (NESDIS), National Geophysical Data Center (NGDC)</origin>
        <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
        <title>NOAA/NGDC Seafloor Sediment Grain Size Database</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>The NGDC grain size database contains particle size data for over 17,000 seafloor samples worldwide. The file was begun by NGDC in 1976 in response to a need by the Outer Continental Shelf Environmental Assessment Program (OCSEAP) for a detailed, digital file of textural analyses. Data are from OCSEAP studies, academic institutions, environmental baseline studies conducted under contract to the Bureau of Land Management for the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) Program, and from laboratory reports generated by the US Navy.</p>
        <p>Data include collecting institution, ship, cruise, sample id, latitude/longitude, date of collection, water depth, sampling device, method of analysis, sample weight, sampled interval, raw weight percentages of sediment, within a given phi range. Some samples also have percentages of total gravel, sand, silt, clay, and statistical measurements such as mean, median, skewness, kurtosis, and standard deviation of grain size. Most size data have been checked for gross percentage mismatches and highly questionable data sets are noted. However, statistics were generated by the originators and have not been verified by NGDC. NGDC is not responsible for errors in the data.</p>
        <p>The Grain Size Database is fully searchable online. Searches return data in a tab-delimited form suitable for upload into most spreadsheet and database applications. Many additional data sets available through NGDC contain grain size data that are not included in this database; some are in paper reports, other data are in diverse formats.</p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>Scientific research.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19500101</begdate>
          <enddate>19901231</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-180</westbc>
        <eastbc>180</eastbc>
        <northbc>90</northbc>
        <southbc>-90</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Benthic</themekey>
        <themekey>Geology</themekey>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>OCSEAP BLM/OCS Studies marine sediment</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None.</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Moore, Carla</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>325 Broadway E/GC3</address>
          <city>Boulder</city>
          <state>CO</state>
          <postal>80303-3328</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>303-497-6339</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>303-497-6513</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Carla.J.Moore@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Moore, Carla</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>325 Broadway E/GC3</address>
          <city>Boulder</city>
          <state>CO</state>
          <postal>80303-3328</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>303-497-6339</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>303-497-6513</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Carla.J.Moore@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19980803</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None.</metac>
    <metuc>None</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
