<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (OAR), Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory (PMEL)</origin>
        <pubdate>1995</pubdate>
        <title>The June - July 1993 Seismo-acoustic Event at CoAxial segment, Juan de Fuca Ridge: Evidence for a Lateral Dike Injection</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The CoAxial segment (Juan de Fuca Ridge) was the site of an intense swarm of earthquakes that began at 21:43 GMT on June 26, 1993 (Julian Day 177). The
swarm started near 46°15N and migrated northward over the next 40 hours to ~46°36N, where the majority of 676 events occurred during the following 3 weeks
of activity. The earthquakes propagated NNE at a velocity of 0.3 ﾱ 0.1 m s from the southern to northern swarm sites. The activity went undetected by land-based
seismic networks along the Oregon and Washington coasts, suggesting that the earthquakes were all M  4.0. The character of this earthquake swarm is very similar
to dike injections observed at Krafla and Kilauea Volcanoes. The earthquake activity and subsequent migration probably represent a lateral dike injection into faults
and fissures comprising the CoAxial segment. The reservoir acting as the dike's source likely resides beneath, or to the south of, the initial southern swarm of
earthquakes. The large magma supply at Axial Volcano cannot be ruled out as the source for the CoAxial dike, even though Axial Volcano exhibited no earthquake
activity related to the CoAxial swarm. The T-wave earthquake swarm reported here is the first deep-ocean observation of volcanic seismicity associated with what
most likely was a mid-ocean ridge dike injection event.</abstract>
      <purpose />
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-128</westbc>
        <eastbc>-128</eastbc>
        <northbc>46.5</northbc>
        <southbc>46.5</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Dziak, Robert P.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>2030 S Marine Science Drive</address>
          <city>Newport</city>
          <state>OR</state>
          <postal>97365</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>541-867-0175</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>Robert.P.Dziak@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Dziak, Robert P.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>2030 S Marine Science Drive</address>
          <city>Newport</city>
          <state>OR</state>
          <postal>97365</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>541-867-0175</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>Robert.P.Dziak@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20010308</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
