<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Gerald Sanger, National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA)</origin>
        <pubdate>19720101</pubdate>
        <title>Fishery Potentials and Estimated Biological Productivity of the Subarctic Pacific Region</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>Pertinent literature on the primary production and fishery potentials of the Subarctic Pacific region are reviewed.  An original estimate of the annual primary production of the region (1.28 x 10 to the 9th tons C/year) is derived and relations of present fish production with estimated potential biological productivity are discussed.</p>
        <p>Assuming a simplified food chain relation for biological production, the potential fish production (not harvest) of the Region is estimated at 26-78 million tons/yr.  Assuming 50% is potentially harvestable, the current average landings (6.6 million tons/yr) would have to be increased four-fold to equal this potential.</p>
        <p>
          Salmon (genus
          <I>Oncorhynchus</I>
          ) are economically important to Canada, Japan, the United States, and the U.S.S.R., but they appear to play a small role in the ecology of the region (except for certain times and places).  Landings for the Region have been stable at about 0.4 million tons/yr.  An assumed total production (catch+escapement+mortality) of 1.2 million tons/yr equals about 1.5% of the estimated total fishery potential.
        </p>
        <p>The scarcity of reliable basic information on oceanic ecology, essential for studies such as this, is briefly discussed.</p>
        <p>[Reference: Sanger, Gerald A. Fishery Potentials and Estimated Biological Productivity of the Subarctic Pacific Region. in A. Y. Takenouti, A. Y., ed. Biological oceanography of the northern North Pacific Ocean. Dedicated to Dr. Sigeru Motoda in commemoration of his contribution to marine biology. Tokyo, Idemitsu Shoten, 1972.] Reprint available at the NOAA Seattle NMML Library.</p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>Collected data revealing Fishery potentials and estimated biological productivity of the Subarctic Pacific region</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19580101</begdate>
          <enddate>19671231</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>140</westbc>
        <eastbc>-120</eastbc>
        <northbc>65</northbc>
        <southbc>34</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Fish</themekey>
        <themekey>Biological Effects</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Subarctic</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Sea of Okhotsk</themekey>
        <themekey>Sea of Japan/East Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NMML Library</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4013</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6615</cntfax>
        <cntemail>nmml.library@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NMML Library</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4013</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6615</cntfax>
        <cntemail>nmml.library@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990125</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>None</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
