<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>University of Alaska Fairbanks (UAF), School of Fisheries and Ocean Sciences (SFOS), Institute of Marine Science (IMS)</origin>
        <pubdate>Planned</pubdate>
        <title>Process Modeling of the Alaska Coastal Current</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>We seek understanding of the dynamic response of the Gulf of Alaska shelf to a distributed coastal buoyancy influx and downwelling winds. Simple process-type numerical models will be used to resolve the basic dynamic balances and capture the
cross-shelf circulation pattern. Parameter ranges used in modeling will encompass  seasonal variations in winds, buoyancy, and stratification of the Alaska Coastal Current (ACC). Results should shed light on a number of issues relevant to
the ecosystems of the Gulf of Alaska and the Bering Sea. We seek to provide a physical explanation for the observed high biological productivity of this deep shelf. The basis for this production is enigmatic given that downwelling winds prevail throughout most of the year and that the shelf receives a massive coastal influx of nutrient-poor freshwater. The ACC appears to be a crucial habitat for young-of-the-year salmon migrating to the ocean. Physical processes within the ACC could enhance the aggregation of zooplankton and therefore be critical to salmon recruitment success. Passive tracers will be introduced into the model to mimic zooplankton and/or young-of-the-year salmon. The dispersion of these tracers will show how these organisms are either retained within the ACC or dispersed outside this current. The results should benefit fisheries biologists seeking to understand salmon  recruitment processes that depends upon survival during their first year. Finally, the ACC plays a crucial role in the freshwater balance of the Gulf of Alaska and possibly the Bering Sea shelf, which lies downstream of the Gulf of Alaska and ultimately receives the ACC. The major focus of the proposed work is on the processes that control the along- and cross-shore transport of freshwater and, conversely, the onshore transport of nutrient-rich, high salinity water from offshore.

This work will be performed by a graduate student (William J. Williams).

An NPMR project</abstract>
      <purpose>Proposal "to develop process models of the Alaska Coastal Current" sent to NPMR</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19990701</begdate>
          <enddate>20010731</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Planned</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>167</westbc>
        <eastbc>-163</eastbc>
        <northbc>67</northbc>
        <southbc>53</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Alaska Coastal Current (ACC)</themekey>
        <themekey>Zooplankton</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska Coast</themekey>
        <themekey>Ocean Currents</themekey>
        <themekey>Models</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Unknown</accconst>
    <useconst>Unknown</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Weingartner, Thomas J.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 757220</address>
          <city>Fairbanks</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99775-7220</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>weingart@ims.uaf.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Weingartner, Thomas J.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 757220</address>
          <city>Fairbanks</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99775-7220</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>weingart@ims.uaf.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20000307</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Unknown</metac>
    <metuc>Unknown</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
