<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>University of Washington (UW), Department of Atmospheric Sciences</origin>
        <pubdate>19970930</pubdate>
        <title>The Contribution of Organized Roll Vortices to the Surface Wind Vector in Baroclinic Conditions</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Observations show that, for a given geostrophic forcing, baroclinity acting on
     the planetary boundary layer produces a nearly sinusoidal modification of the
     near-surface wind. Compared to barotropic conditions the speed is enhanced in
     the direction of the thermal wind and the cross-isobar angle increases (decreases)
     in cold (warm) advection. These modifications are asymmetric with respect to the
     thermal wind orientation. Two-layer similarity models that match a
     stratification-dependent surface layer to a stratification and baroclinity dependent
     Ekman layer simulate aspects of this asymmetric baroclinic modification if the cold
     advection conditions are more unstably stratified than the warm advection
     conditions. The authors demonstrate that roll vortices in a baroclinic planetary
     boundary layer produce an asymmetric surface wind modification in neutral
     stratification that can work in concert with the coupling between stratification and
     baroclinity to enhance the net effect of baroclinity on the surface wind. It is further
     demonstrated that the roll modification effect can be as much as or even more that
     the pure thermal wind effect, although both are secondary to the pure frictional
     effect. This baroclinic roll modification works to increase the low-level poleward
     mass transport and the near-surface westerly momentum in the midlatitudes.</abstract>
      <purpose>The Contribution of Organized Roll Vortices to the Surface Wind Vector in Baroclinic Conditions</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19970930</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Barents Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Wind</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Foster, Ralph C.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>University of Washington - Dept of Atmos. Sci.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98112</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Foster, Ralph C.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>University of Washington - Dept of Atmos. Sci.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98112</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990204</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
