<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>McGill University, Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences and Centre for Climate and Global Change Research</origin>
        <pubdate>19970401</pubdate>
        <title>Modeling Sea Ice as a Granular Material, Including  the Dilatancy Effect</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>A dynamic sea ice model based on granular material rheology is
     presented. The sea ice model is coupled to both a mixed layer ocean model
     and a one-layer thermodynamic atmospheric model, which allows for an ice
     albedo feedback. Land is represented by a 6-m thick layer with a constant
     base temperature. A 10-year integration including both thermodynamic and
     dynamic effects and incorporating prescribed climatological wind stress and
     ocean current data was performed in order for the model to reach a stable
     periodic seasonal cycle. The commonly observed lead complexes, along
     which sliding and opening of adjacent ice floes occur in the Arctic sea ice
     cover, are well reproduced in this simulation. In particular, shear lines
     extending from the western Canadian Archipelago toward the central Arctic,
     often observed in winter satellite images, are present. The ice edge is well
     positioned both in winter and summer using this thermodynamically coupled
     oceanﾖiceﾖatmosphere model. The results also yield a sea ice circulation and
     thickness distribution over the Arctic, which are in good agreement with
     observations. The model also produces an increase in ice formation
     associated with the dilatation of the ice medium along sliding lines. In this
     model, incident energy absorbed by the ocean melts ice laterally and warms
     the mixed layer, causing a smaller ice retreat in the summer. This cures a
     problem common to many existing thermodynamicﾖdynamic sea ice models</abstract>
      <purpose>To show the modeling Sea Ice as a Granular Material, Including  the Dilatancy Effect</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19970401</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Sea Ice</themekey>
        <themekey>Models</themekey>
        <themekey>Chukchi Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Tremblay, L.B.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>3600 McTavish, Office 1200</address>
          <city>Montreal</city>
          <state>Quebec</state>
          <postal />
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Tremblay, L.B.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>3600 McTavish, Office 1200</address>
          <city>Montreal</city>
          <state>Quebec</state>
          <postal />
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990205</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
