<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>University of Alaska Fairbanks (UAF), School of Fisheries and Ocean Sciences (SFOS), Institute of Marine Science (IMS)</origin>
        <pubdate>Unpublished Material</pubdate>
        <title>Summertime Plankton Community Structure and Trophic Dynamics in the SE Bering Sea Shelf: Importance for Nutrient Cycling and Prey Production for Planktivorous Fishes</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>To date, most lower trophic level research on the eastern Bering Sea shelf has concentrated on the role of the spring diatom bloom as the main annual production event. Over the Middle Shelf Domain, primary and secondary productions occur
throughout the summer supported by regenerated nutrients. During this period, standing stock of chlorophyll is relatively low (0.5 - 2 µg/l). Periodic outbreaks of diatoms can occur in response to erosion of the pycnocline and injection of nitrate and silicate
into the surface waters. Between these outbreaks, nano- and microzooplankton (&lt;200 µm) are hypothesized to dominate nutrient cycling. During these periods microzooplankton may also provide the intermediary link between small flagellated primary producers and food for juvenile fishes. Recent recurring "blooms"
of the coccolithophore Emiliania huxleyi require us to achieve a better understanding of summertime nutrient recycling and trophic transfer so that we can predict the effect, if any, E. huxleyi will have on higher trophic levels. We plan to dissect the summer pelagic food web and nutrient cycle of the Middle Shelf Domain to determine the relative
contribution of microzooplankton to these processes. Specifically we will investigate nutrient cycling and trophic transfer during two distinct phytoplankton communities: small flagellates (coccolithophores or other species) and diatoms. Juvenile Pollock, a nodal species in the Bering Sea ecosystem, forage on particle-grazing mesozooplankton and variations in summer food supply may affect their ability to accumulate energy stores for the harsh Subarctic winters.

This project also includes;

Evelyn Lessard 
University of Washington 

Jeffrey Napp 
Alaska Fisheries Science Center, NOAA 
7600 Sand Point Way NE
Seattle, WA  98115
jeff.napp@noaa.gov
An NPMR project</abstract>
      <purpose>A proposal to North Pacific Marine Research Program. An NPMR project.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19990701</begdate>
          <enddate>20020731</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Planned</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>167</westbc>
        <eastbc>-163</eastbc>
        <northbc>67</northbc>
        <southbc>53</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Fish</themekey>
        <themekey>Biology</themekey>
        <themekey>Plankton</themekey>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Bering Sea Shelf</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Unknown</accconst>
    <useconst>Unknown</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Whitledge, Terry E.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 757220</address>
          <city>Fairbanks</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99775-7220</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-474-7229</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>terry@ims.uaf.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Whitledge, Terry E.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 757220</address>
          <city>Fairbanks</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99775-7220</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-474-7229</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>terry@ims.uaf.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20000202</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Unknown</metac>
    <metuc>Unknown</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
