<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (OAR), Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory (PMEL)</origin>
        <pubdate>19811231</pubdate>
        <title>Circulation and Hydrography of Norton Sound</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Norton Sound was two-layered vertically in temperature and salinity during summer, the eastern portion being more strongly layered than the western. Weak cyclonic mean flow in the eastern upper layer was not reflected in the lower layer, which was nearly stagnant and contained remnant cold, saline water formed locally during winter. Maintenance of this extreme layering in the eastern sound despite shallow depths (~15 m) was due to buoyancy input as solar heating and fresh water, sufficient to offset vertical mixing generated by tidal currents. In the western sound, coupled northerly upper- and lower-layer flows reflected a northward net flow over the shelf west of the sound. At times a strong baroclinic coastal flow occurred off Nome, and the central western sound was a locus for vertical mixing due to impingement of currents upon a shoal area. During winter, the sound approached vertical homogeneity due to vertical convection consequent to cooling and ice formation. Although it was possible to define mean flows, the currents were dominated by events which reflected regional wind and atmospheric pressure patterns in an as yet uncertain fashion. Such flow events may exert a primary control over such features as the Yukon River plume, which was never observed to enter the eastern sound even though the upper-layer salinity there suggests that Yukon water may have entered the sound prior to our observations.</abstract>
      <purpose>To report the circulation and hydrography of Norton Sound</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19811231</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Circulation</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Norton Sound</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with this URLs : http://www.pmel.noaa.gov/pubs/publications.shtml</accconst>
    <useconst>Refer to webstite URL: http://www.pmel.noaa.gov/pubs/publications.shtml</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Muench, Robin D.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Muench, Robin D.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990203</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with this URLs : http://www.pmel.noaa.gov/pubs/publications.shtml</metac>
    <metuc>Refer to webstite URL: http://www.pmel.noaa.gov/pubs/publications.shtml</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
