<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>University of Washington (UW), Joint Institute for the Study of Atmosphere and Ocean (JISAO)</origin>
        <pubdate>1988</pubdate>
        <title>Prefrontal and Postfrontal Boundary Layer Processes over the Ocean</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Measurements taken during the Storm Transfer and Response Experiment (STREX) are used to analyze boundary layer structures and processes in North Pacific storms. Heat and moisture transfers at the surface and through the top of the boundary layer are evaluated for three cases with warm, southerly flow ahead of cold fronts and two cases of cooler, westerly and northern flow behind fronts. The prefrontal boundary layers are nearly neutrally stratified and surface heat and moisture fluxes are small. Surface fluxes tend to be downward just ahead of the fronts and are of greater magnitude during stronger storms. Entrainment fluxes at the top of the prefrontal boundary layers are generally larger than surface fluxes and are the dominant sources of heating for the boundary layers. Entrainment rates determined from budgets compare well with laboratory studies of shear-driven entrainment. In the postfrontal cases, surface heat and moisture fluxes are the dominant sources of total heating within the boundary layers. Entrainment velocities are larger in postfrontal than prefrontal regions, but entrainment has only a small and positive net effect on the total heat content. In postfrontal transition layers the Richardson numbers are large, and entrainment is forced by turbulence generated by buoyancy in the surface layers and radiative and evaporative cooling from the tops of stratocumulus clouds. Cumulus-scale penetrative convection represents the major sink of boundary layer moisture for one case with a long atmospheric fetch over the ocean.</abstract>
      <purpose />
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>110</westbc>
        <eastbc>-77</eastbc>
        <northbc>70</northbc>
        <southbc>0</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Atmosphere</themekey>
        <themekey>Meteorology</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Storm Transfer and Response Experiment (STREX)</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Bond, Nicholas A.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>4909 25th Ave NE, first floor - (JISAO)</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98195-4235</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6459</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Nickolas.A.Bond@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Bond, Nicholas A.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>4909 25th Ave NE, first floor - (JISAO)</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98195-4235</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6459</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>Nickolas.A.Bond@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20010301</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
