<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>University of Alaska Fairbanks (UAF)</origin>
        <pubdate>Planned</pubdate>
        <title>Concentrations of Mercury and its Food Chain and Geochemical Pathways to Selected Commercial and Subsistence Marine Organisms of Eastern Bering Sea</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The presence of a variety of contaminants has been reported in environmental samples of the eastern Bering Sea. The contaminant of greatest concern is mercury (Hg), in light of the high levels of this element reported in some marine sediments and organisms of the sea and contiguous fluvial estuaries. We hypothesize that several unique environmental conditions, coupled with high natural supply of terrigenous Hg, result in high bioaccumulation of this element in marine organisms of the Bering Sea region with ultimate potential risk to commercial and subsistence users.  The primary objective of the study is to check whether the concentrations of Hg in some commercial and subsistence organisms in the Bering Sea are at levels that pose a risk to the organisms and are unacceptable for human consumption. To fulfill this objective we will analyze the concentrations of total Hg [Hg(t)] and its more toxic form, methylmercury (MeHg), in
selected commercial and subsistence organisms of the Bering Sea (salmon, king crab, and clams). This study deals with issues considered a high priority by the Bering Sea Marine Research Plan (1998) as well as by several state and federal agencies and Bering Sea native groups.

This project also includes;

John Kelley 
School of Fisheries and Ocean Sciences
245 O'Neill Building
University of Alaska Fairbanks
Fairbanks, AK 99775-7220

An NPMR project</abstract>
      <purpose>A proposal to NPMR to show the effects of concentrations of mercury and its food chain and geochemical pathways to selected commercial and subsistence marine organisms of eastern Bering Sea</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19990701</begdate>
          <enddate>20010731</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Planned</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>167</westbc>
        <eastbc>-163</eastbc>
        <northbc>67</northbc>
        <southbc>53</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Food Chain</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Unknown</accconst>
    <useconst>Unknown</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Naidu, Sathy</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 757220</address>
          <city>Fairbanks</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99775-7220</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-474-7824</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>907-474-7204</cntfax>
        <cntemail>ffsan@uaf.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Naidu, Sathy</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 757220</address>
          <city>Fairbanks</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99775-7220</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-474-7824</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>907-474-7204</cntfax>
        <cntemail>ffsan@uaf.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20000307</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Unknown</metac>
    <metuc>Unknown</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
