<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Memorial University Newfoundland, Ocean Science Centre</origin>
        <pubdate>19931231</pubdate>
        <title>The Trophic Organization of the Marine Bird Community in the Bering Sea</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Bays and semi-enclosed seas provide a natural spatial scale at which to characterize the trophic organization of marine communities. This article summarizes the information available on the trophic organization (species number, relative abundance, seasonal abundance, foraging style, and diet) of the marine bird community at the spatial scale of the entire Bering Sea. This required synthesizing work in English (pertaining to the east) and Russian (pertaining to the west), much of it published after 1980. A total of 51 seabird species (not counting loons, grebes, and seaducks) regularly inhabit the Bering Sea. Based on work available (to 1990), the minimum number of breeding seabirds in the western Bering Sea is 3.1 x 10 super(6) along the Asian coast (Cape Kamchatskiy to the Bering Strait), 10 super(6) in the
 Commander Islands, 1.1 x 10 super(7) in the Aleutian Islands, and 1.2 x 10 super(7) along the North American coast (Unimak Pass to the Bering Strait). Nonbreeding seabirds include 3 species of albatross, 3 pagophilic gulls, and on the order of 3.3 x 10 super(7) Puffinus shearwaters. Seasonal movements are primarily meridional (north-south) and strongly tied to the breeding cycle. Major foraging styles include surface gleaning (as in fulmars), bottom gleaning (as in cormorants), and mid-water pursuit (as in murres). Major prey resources include euphausiids, squid, immature fish (notably Walleye Pollock), and copepods. The data show that less than five avian species account for most of the energy flux to the avian community. The data indicate that this flux is strongly seasonal and highly localized in space. Localized seasonal concentrations of invertebrates (notably euphausiids and copepods) appear to be more important sources of energy flux to birds in this ecosystem than at lower latitudes.</abstract>
      <purpose>A report on the trophic organization of the marine bird community in the Bering Sea</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19931231</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Birds</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Trawling Fisheries</themekey>
        <themekey>Marine Related</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Schneider, D.C.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Memorial Univ. Newfoundland</address>
          <city>St. John</city>
          <state>Newfoundland</state>
          <postal>A1B 3X7</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Schneider, D.C.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Memorial Univ. Newfoundland</address>
          <city>St. John</city>
          <state>Newfoundland</state>
          <postal>A1B 3X7</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990204</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
