<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), Alaska Fisheries Science Center (AFSC)</origin>
        <pubdate>19941231</pubdate>
        <title>Comparisons of Walleye Pollock, Theragra chalcogramma, Harvest to Steller Sea Lion, Eumetopias jubatus, Abundance in the Bering Sea and Gulf of Alaska.</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Steller sea lion, Eumetopias jubatus, counts made on rookeries
                        in the Gulf of Alaska, Aleutian Islands, and the Bering Sea from
                        1976 to 1991 were compared to annual estimates of walleye
                        Pollock, Theragra chalcogramma, harvest to examine possible
                        relationships between Steller sea lion abundance and commercial
                        Pollock fishing. Comparisons were made between Steller sea lion
                        counts and Pollock fishery data from the same year and from 1 to
                        5 years prior. Two sets of study areas were used, one
                        encompassing 60 nmi or 120 nmi blocks around six major
                        rookeries and another with 13 sites defined by 20 nmi radius rings
                        around major rookeries. Lacking accurate measures of local
                        Pollock biomass, harvest data were used as approximations of
                        annual differences in Pollock abundance. Following methods used
                        in Loughlin and Merrick (1989), correlation coefficients were
                        calculated using a linear model and tested for significance using a
                        2-tailed null hypothesis ( = 0.05). However, since the data are
                        probably not normally distributed, Kendall's coefficients of rank
                        correlation were also calculated and tested for significance            
                        ( = 0.05).

                        Using the parametric approach, some significant positive
                        correlation were obtained comparing sea lion counts to Pollock
                        harvests 1 to 5 years prior (2 in the first set of comparisons and 8
                        in the second). These may indicate circumstances where Pollock
                        abundance was adequate to sustain the fishery while sea lion
                        abundance remained unaffected. Significant negative correlation
                        (2 in each set of comparisons) may suggest instances where areas
                        of low Pollock biomass were effectively harvested, but the low or
                        reduced availability of prey, or the fishing activity itself, could have
                        affected Steller sea lion abundance 3 to 5 years later.

                        Only two of the significant correlation found in the parametric
                        approach were detected using Kendall's rank correlation test. We
                        conclude that any potential relationship between sea lion
                        abundance and Pollock harvest can not be properly determined
                        from these data.</abstract>
      <purpose />
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19941231</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Mammals</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>State Plane Zones</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Ferrero, R.C.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Ferrero, R.C.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990311</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>None</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
