<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>North Pacific Marine Science Foundation (North Pacific Universities Marine Mammal Research Consortium)</origin>
        <pubdate>2004</pubdate>
        <title>Assessing the Physiological Stress of Steller Sea Lions Using Fecal Hormone Analysis</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>We validated a fecal glucocorticoid assay for Steller sea lions (Eumetopias jubatus) and estimated stress hormone concentrations from fecal samples collected from sea lions in different regions of Alaska.  Validation was undertaken with an adrenocorticotropic hormone (ACTH) challenge.  Feces were collected from captive Steller sea lions (two males and two females) for two days prior to injection with ACTH, and for four or more days post-injection.  Feces were freeze-dried, extracted with a methanol vortex method, and assayed for glucocorticoids. Fecal samples were also collected in the wild from three separate groups of animals during summer: mature females, mature males and immature animals.  In addition, we collected sea lion feces in winter (Dec-Mar) and summer (May-Sep) from two regions of Alaska: Southeast Alaska (where sea lions increased) and the Gulf of Alaska (where sea lions declined). Diets (determined from the hard parts removed from the scats) and stress hormone concentrations were compared by season and region to test whether there was a relationship between diet and stress. The amount of prey required to meet daily needs was calculated for each haulout and rookery by applying a bioenergetics model to the composition of prey species identified from scats.  The captive study showed that fecal glucocorticoid concentrations can be reliably measured in Steller sea lion feces.  From the summer field study, we found that bulls had higher summer concentrations of stress hormones on average than mature females, which were in turn higher than those of immature sea lions.  In general, mean consumption of prey (all sites combined) was higher in winter than in summer, as were mean stress hormone concentrations.  Similarly, consumption was higher in Southeast Alaska than in the Gulf of Alaska, as too were stress hormone concentrations.  The lower levels of stress hormones detected in the Gulf of Alaska and the relatively high energy content of their diets in 2000 is inconsistent with the nutritional stress hypothesis and the continued population decline of Steller sea lions.  Such a finding adds credence to the view that killer whale predation may now be preventing population recovery.  [ An NPMR project ]

  [ Reference: Hunt, K.E., A.W. Trites, and S.K. Wasser. 2004. Validation of a fecal glucocorticoid assay for Steller sea lions (Eumetopias jubatus). Physiology and Behavior 80: 595-601. ]</abstract>
      <purpose>To validate a fecal glucocorticoid assay for Steller sea lions and estimated stress hormone concentrations from fecal samples collected from sea lions in different regions of Alaska to assess whether stress hormone concentrations correlate with season and rates of population change.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19990801</begdate>
          <enddate>20000731</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>In Progress</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>167</westbc>
        <eastbc>-163</eastbc>
        <northbc>67</northbc>
        <southbc>53</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Biology</themekey>
        <themekey>Biological Effects</themekey>
        <themekey>Mammals</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Unknown</accconst>
    <useconst>Unknown</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Trites, Andrew W.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>6248 Biological Sciences Road</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6T IZ4</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-822-8181</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-822-8180</cntfax>
        <cntemail>trites@zoology.ubc.ca</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Trites, Andrew W.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>6248 Biological Sciences Road</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6T IZ4</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-822-8181</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-822-8180</cntfax>
        <cntemail>trites@zoology.ubc.ca</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19991123</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Unknown</metac>
    <metuc>Unknown</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
