<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Korea Ocean Research and Development Institute (KORDI), Polar Research Center</origin>
        <pubdate>19960501</pubdate>
        <title>Surface Phytoplankton in the Bering Sea During the Summer of 1994 and 1995: Relationships to Physical and Chemical Environmental Parameters.</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Surface Phytoplankton with their physiochemical environments were sampled in the international zone of the Bering Sea and in the Bogoslof Island region during summer (July) 1994 and 1995.  Surface chl a concentrations ranged from 0.54 to 10.2mug(-1) during the study period.  Areas with the higher chl a values (3.4-10.2mugl(-1)) were located in the continental shelf break and in the Bogoslof Island region.  Waters in the Bogoslof were characterized by a dominance of microplanktonic (&gt;20mu) diatoms such as Corethron criphilum, Chaetoceros spp., Rhizosolenia spp.  The highest chl a value was measured at Station 6 in the Bogoslof with 10.2mugl (-1) which was about 15 to 20 times higher value compared to that in the international zone of the Bering Sea.  It is speculated that such a high Phytoplankton biomass in the Bogoslof region was caused by water column stability which was developed near the continental shelf break.  Less saline waters (32.2-32.5%) in the northeastern part for the Bering Sea seem to be intruded to the open waters and created a front to cause increase of Phytoplankton biomass.  Surface temperature ranged from 5.3 to 8.7 (average 7.2 ± 0.6 C) in 1994 and from 9.8 to 12.4 C (average 10.7 ± 0.8 C) in 1995, respectively. Surface temperatures showed weak influence on Phytoplankton distribution, but about 3 C surface temperature difference between 1994 and 1995 may affect on the phytoplankton growth.  Mean values of major nutrients such as nitrate, phosphate and silicate were 6.2 ±3.2 mu, 0.87 ±0.4mu, 14.5 ±7.0mu in 1994, respectively.  With increase of Phytoplankton decrease of the major nutrients was observed.</abstract>
      <purpose />
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19960501</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-165</westbc>
        <eastbc>-158</eastbc>
        <northbc>67</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Phytoplankton</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Blooms</themekey>
        <themekey>China Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kang, Sung-Ho</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 29, Ansan</address>
          <city>Seoul</city>
          <state />
          <postal>425-600</postal>
          <country>Republic of Korea</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kang, Sung-Ho</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 29, Ansan</address>
          <city>Seoul</city>
          <state />
          <postal>425-600</postal>
          <country>Republic of Korea</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990716</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>None</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
