<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Department of Fisheries and Oceans, Institute of Ocean Sciences</origin>
        <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
        <title>CDIAC - U.S. DOE Global Survey of CO2 in the Ocean</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Parameter
Total alkalinity, pC02 and other carbon measurements

Measurement Details
"Although the total CO2 (TCO2) is not an official WOCE measurement, a coordinated effort, supported in the USA by the Department of Energy (DOE), is being made on WOCE cruises through 1998 to measure the global spatial and temporal distributions of TCO2 and other related parameters. Goals of the survey are to estimate the meridional transport of inorganic carbon in a manner analogous to the oceanic heat transport, and to build a data base suitable for carbon cycle modeling and the estimation of anthropogenic CO2 increase in the oceans. The CO2 survey is taking advantage of the sampling opportunities provided by the WHP cruises during this period. The final data set is expected to cover ~23,000 stations from 42 WOCE cruises. 
The Carbon Dioxide Information Analysis Center (CDIAC) at Oak Ridge National Laboratory (ORNL) provides data management support for the Joint Global Ocean Flux Studies (JGOFS) carbon dioxide (CO2) measurements taken aboard research vessels during World Ocean Circulation Experiment Hydrographic Program cruises. The U.S. DOE sponsored CO2 measurement operations and continues to sponsor CDIAC's data support activities, which include data archival, data checking and evaluation, preparation of data documentation, and data dissemination. All CO2-related data are checked before documentation and distribution. As of today, DOE GCRP-supported investigators had collected CO2 measurements on 42 WOCE cruises. CDIAC has received data from 38 of these cruises, and 25 of these data sets have undergone quality assurance checks with 10 of them being fully documented as numeric data packages (NDPs)."  

Base Internet/URL ( http://cdiac.esd.ornl.gov/cdiac/oceans/home.html ) ( http://cdiac.esd.ornl.gov/cdiac/oceans/table.html )  

[ A TCODE project ]</abstract>
      <purpose />
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19810101</begdate>
          <enddate>19991231</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As Needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>165</westbc>
        <eastbc>-165</eastbc>
        <northbc>67</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Topography</themekey>
        <themekey>Pathfinder</themekey>
        <themekey>
          Carbon Dioxide (CO
          <sub>2</sub>
          )
        </themekey>
        <themekey>Physical Chemical Oceanography</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Inventories, sampling distribution maps, summary data and Numerical Data Products (NDP) available from this web site.</accconst>
    <useconst>None</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Brown, Robin</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 6000</address>
          <city>Sidney</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V81 4B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-363-6584</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-363-6390</cntfax>
        <cntemail>rmbrown@ios.bc.ca</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Brown, Robin</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 6000</address>
          <city>Sidney</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V81 4B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-363-6584</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-363-6390</cntfax>
        <cntemail>rmbrown@ios.bc.ca</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990813</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Inventories, sampling distribution maps, summary data and Numerical Data Products (NDP) available from this web site.</metac>
    <metuc>None</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
