<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Nagoya University, Institute for HydrosphericﾖAtmospheric Sciences</origin>
        <pubdate>19970516</pubdate>
        <title>A Dual-Doppler Radar Study of Longitudinal-Mode Snowbands. Part I: A Three-Dimensional Kinematic Structure of Meso--Scale Connective Cloud Systems within a Longitudinal-Mode Snowband</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Observations of snowstorms were carried out around Ishikari Bay, Hokkaido,
     Japan, from December 1991 to February 1992. On 15 January 1992, a
     longitudinal-mode snowband was observed by a dual-Doppler radar system. The
     snowband was composed of meso--scale (20 km) connective cloud
     systems. The three-dimensional kinematic structures and organization processes
     of the meso--scale systems were studied in detail.

       Strong band-parallel winds appeared in the upper-north rear of the
     meso--scale systems. Since their speed was faster than that of the cellular radar
     echoes, the winds formed rear-to-front currents. Increasing in volume and speed,
     the rear-to-front currents developed into meso- scale and penetrated toward
     the lower front and lower south of the systems. Consequently, the rear-to-front
     currents caused strong meso--scale convergence and the enhancement of
     updrafts at their leading edges. The transport of the band-parallel momentum
     greatly contributed to the successive development of new connective cells within
     the systems and the organization of the meso--scale systems in the snowband.
     Ice/snow particles were transported by the updrafts toward the rear and north of
     the systems in the overlying stable layer. They then evaporated outside the clouds.
     The downdraft caused by evaporative cooling played an important role in the
     transport of band-parallel momentum from the upper to the lower levels and from
     the outside to the inside of the snowband.</abstract>
      <purpose>To report on Dual-Doppler Radar Study of Longitudinal-Mode Snowbands. Part I: A Three-Dimensional Kinematic Structure of Meso--Scale Connective Cloud Systems within a Longitudinal-Mode Snowband</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19970516</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Atmosphere</themekey>
        <themekey>Meteorology</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Acoustic Surveys</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Doppler Data</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Fujiyoshi, Yasushi</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Institute for HydrosphericﾖAtmospheric Sciences</address>
          <city>Nagoya</city>
          <state />
          <postal />
          <country>Japan</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Fujiyoshi, Yasushi</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Institute for HydrosphericﾖAtmospheric Sciences</address>
          <city>Nagoya</city>
          <state />
          <postal />
          <country>Japan</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990204</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
