<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA)</origin>
        <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
        <title>2002 (May - Jul.) U.S. 2002 Crab and Groundfish Survey Data of the Eastern Bering Sea (Cruise ID: A/A2002-01)</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>The Bering Sea Resource Assessment group completed its annual shelf crab-groundfish bottom trawl survey during 29 May - 1 August 2002.  This yearﾒs survey was performed aboard the chartered fishing vessels Arcturus and Aldebaran.  This marks the 10th consecutive survey using these vessels.</p>
        <p>A total of 393 stations were sampled, including 18 special stations from inner Bristol Bay, to continue our evaluation of yellowfin sole spawning populations during the sampling period.  Abundance estimates for the major species showed few unexpected changes from 2001.</p>
        <p>Seawater temperature profiles were collected at most sampling sites using a micro-bathythermograph attached to the headrope of the net. Surface seawater temperatures were also collected with a bucket thermometer. Sampling was carried out in the Pribilof Islands and St. Matthew Island regions to collect additional data on crab populations. Additional stations north of the standard survey area were established to estimate the abundance of Tanner crab (C. opilio) in that area.</p>
        <p>Biological data were collected at alternate north/south columns of stations proceeding from Bristol Bay westward to the shelf edge. All catches were sorted to the lowest possible taxon, weighed, and enumerated. Station data including time, position, trawl performance, distance fished as well as catch information was entered onto diskettes with shipboard computer systems. Age samples (by sex-centimeter category), size composition, and other biological data were collected from the major fish species  encountered. Length-width measurements, shell condition, clutch size, and tissues and organs for various studies were collected from the major crab species. Special study collections were stored in appropriate fixatives or were frozen.</p>
        <p>
          Cruise ID: A/A2002-01 (May 29 - July 2002)
          <br />
          Chartered commercial vessels
          <em>F/S Aldebaran and Arcturus</em>
        </p>
        <p>For cruise results see http://www.afsc.noaa.gov/race/surveys/cruise_archives/cruises2002/rsltsA-A2002-01.pdf</p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>To continue the annual series of assessment surveys of crab and groundfish of the eastern Bering Sea that began in 1971.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20020529</begdate>
          <enddate>20020724</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As Needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-178.16</westbc>
        <eastbc>-157.97</eastbc>
        <northbc>62</northbc>
        <southbc>54.67</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Fish</themekey>
        <themekey>Management</themekey>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Flounder</themekey>
        <themekey>Plaice</themekey>
        <themekey>Sculpin</themekey>
        <themekey>Skate</themekey>
        <themekey>Perch</themekey>
        <themekey>Sea Temperature</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
        <themekey>Crabs</themekey>
        <themekey>Halibut</themekey>
        <themekey>Groundfish</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Bristol Bay, Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Pribilof Islands</themekey>
        <themekey>St. Matthew Island</themekey>
        <themekey>Pollock</themekey>
        <themekey>Sole</themekey>
        <themekey>Cod</themekey>
        <themekey>Flatfish</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor or Source.</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor or Source.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Stauffer, Gary</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4170</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6723</cntfax>
        <cntemail>gary.stauffer@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Stauffer, Gary</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4170</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6723</cntfax>
        <cntemail>gary.stauffer@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20030530</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor or Source.</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor or Source.</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
