<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>
          <li>Tomonori Azumaya, Orio Yamamura, Masa-aki Fukuwaka, Akira Kusaka, and Toru Nagasawa of Hokkaido National Fisheries Research Institute, Fisheries Research Agency, Kushiro, Japan</li>
          <li>Shigehiko Urawa and Tetsuichi Nomura of National Salmon Resources Center, Sapport, Japan</li>
          <li>Shogo Moriya of Research and Development Center, Nisshinbo Industry Inc., Chiba, Japan</li>
          <li>Akihisa Urano of Field Science Center for Northern Biosphere, Hokkaido University of Sapporo, Hokkaido, Japan</li>
          <li>North Pacific Anadromous Fish Commission</li>
        </origin>
        <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
        <title>
          Total Lipid Content in the White Muscle of Chum Salmon of the Survey by
          <em>Kaiyo maru</em>
          in Bering Sea, 2002
        </title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>Trawl sampling by R/V Kaiyo maru was conducted 62 trawl operations at 38 stations from June 29 to July 14 (leg 1) and from August 21 to September 18 (leg 3 and 4) in the Bering Sea.</p>
        <p>To measure total lipid (TL) content in the white muscle of chum salmon, TL was extracted from the white muscle of 457 chum salmon using chloroform and methanol and then measured gravimetrically. The TL contained in chum salmon caught in June and July ranged from 0.4% to 15.6% (n=123). The TL contained in chum salmon caught in September ranged from 1.0% to 21.2% (n=334). High lipid content was observed even in small size fish (Fig. 7). There was significant relationship between total lipid content and moisture content in the muscle. High lipid content in September may indicate that late summer is the time when lipid is stored at the expense of growth in order to promote survival through a lean winter.</p>
        <p>Main catches included sockeye (Oncorhynchus nerka), chum (O. keta), chinook salmon (O. tshawytscha), Atka mackerel (Pleurogrammus monopterygius), walleye Pollock (Theragra chalcogramma), and other fishes. A total of 11,446 salmon were captured including pink salmon (O. gorbuscha) (0.1%), chum salmon (89.5%), sockeye salmon (6.4%), coho salmon (O. kisutch) (0.03%) and chinook salmon (3.9%).</p>
        <p>[Reference: Tomonori Azumaya, S. Urawa , O. Yamamura, M. Fukuwaka, A. Kusaka, T. Nagasawa, T. Nomura, S. Moriya, and A. Urano. 2003. Result of the survey by Kaiyo maru in the Bering Sea, 2002. (NPAFC Doc. 717). 12 p. Hokkaido National Fisheries Research Institute, Fisheries Research Agency, 116 Katsurakoi, Kushiro 085-0802, Japan.] This report is available for download at http://www.npafc.org/restricted_doc/2003%20Documents_PDF/717(Japan).pdf</p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>To investigate the environments for salmon habitat and distributions of salmon in the Bering Sea.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <mdattim>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>20020629 - 20020714, 20020821 - 20020918</caldate>
          </sngdate>
        </mdattim>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>172</westbc>
        <eastbc>-165</eastbc>
        <northbc>59</northbc>
        <southbc>51.5</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Fish</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Chum Salmon</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Total Lipid</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>Contact Source.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20050225</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>Contact Source.</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
