<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>University of Alaska Fairbanks (UAF), School of Fisheries and Ocean Sciences (SFOS), Institute of Marine Science (IMS)</origin>
        <pubdate>19921231</pubdate>
        <title>A Review: Walleye Pollock in the North Pacific - How Much Difference Do They Really Make?</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Populations of several species of marine birds and mammals in the Bering Sea and Gulf of Alaska have been declining since the mid-1970s, with numbers of one, the Steller sea lion (Eumetopias jubatus), so depressed it was listed as threatened under the Endangered Species Act in spring 1990.  All of the declining populations depend to an important extent on walleye Pollock (Theragra chalcogramma) for food, although they eat numerous other species as well. In contrast, certain animals that compete with Pollock for common prey have been increasing in abundance. All of these changes could be related through food web connections mediated by Pollock. Pollock is also
important to people--it presently supports the largest single-species commercial fishery in the world, in large part because of its great biomass, which has averaged about 15 x 10 super(6) t in the Bering Sea over the past 15 years. Pollock consume an inordinate proportion of the pelagic production  in the Bearing Sea, which further supports the conclusion that it is a key species in the ecosystem. However, there are conflicting hypotheses about the importance of the roles played by Pollock as predator and prey, and about the effect that changes in Pollock abundance might have on biomass yield at higher  trophic levels.</abstract>
      <purpose>A review  on the walleye pollock, on how much difference do they really make in the North Pacific</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19921231</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Walleye Pollock</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Springer, Alan M.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 757220</address>
          <city>Fairbanks</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99775-7220</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-474-7531</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>907-474-5863</cntfax>
        <cntemail>director@ims.alaska.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Springer, Alan M.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 757220</address>
          <city>Fairbanks</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99775-7220</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-474-7531</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>907-474-5863</cntfax>
        <cntemail>director@ims.alaska.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990204</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
