<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (OAR), Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory (PMEL)</origin>
        <pubdate>1982</pubdate>
        <title>Major- and Trace-element Composition of Suspended Matter in the North-east Gulf of Alaska: Relationships with Major Sources</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Seasonal variations of the distributions and chemical compositions of suspended particulate matter in the northeast Gulf of Alaska were studied during 1975-1976.
Selected samples were analyzed for total suspended matter by gravimetry; particulate C and N by dry combustion gas chromatography; and particulate Al, Si, K,
Ca, Ti, Cr, Mn, Fe, Ni, Cu and Zn by thin-film X-ray secondary emission spectrometry. The results showed that suspended material from the Copper River and the
coastal streams which drain the Bering, Guyot, and Malaspina glaciers was carried westward along the coast and deposited in nearshore environments. However,
near Kayak Island, significant quantities of suspended material of terrestrial origin were deflected to the southwest, past the edge of the outer shelf, by an
anticyclonic gyre. The distribution patterns of the major and trace elements in the particulate matter and their elemental ratios with aluminum indicated that: K, Ti, Mn
and Fe were primarily associated with aluminosilicate material and C and N with organic material in all samples; and Si, Ca, Cr, Ni, Cu and Zn were primarily
associated with aluminosilicate material in nearshore surface and near-bottom samples and with organic material in offshore surface samples. Only C, N, Ca, Cu and
Zn showed significant seasonal variations which appeared to be related to biological production of organic matter.</abstract>
      <purpose />
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-145</westbc>
        <eastbc>-130</eastbc>
        <northbc>60</northbc>
        <southbc>55</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Feely, Richard A.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98118</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6214</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>Richard.A.Feely@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Feely, Richard A.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98118</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6214</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>Richard.A.Feely@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20010308</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
