<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Oregon State University (OSU), Hatfield Marine Science Center</origin>
        <pubdate>Planned</pubdate>
        <title>Foraging Habitats and Migration Routes of the North Pacific Right Whale in the Bering Sea</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The right whale is the most endangered of all the large whales. The population in the North Pacific is thought to number only a few hundred individuals and recent sightings in the eastern Bering Sea are the only encouraging sign for this species. We will study these individuals to identify (1) their summer and fall foraging range, (2) their presumed late fall migration route, and (3) their winter habitat. Previous research by our team has
identified North Atlantic right whales, Pacific blue whales, and Pacific humpbacks using oceanographic structures such as upwellings, eddies, and boundary regions as feeding areas. Our hypothesis is that similar areas may also be used by right whales of the North Pacific/Bering Sea.  We propose to tag and track right whales in the Bering Sea
during the next two years using satellite-monitored radio tags to identify these areas. We will correlate whale movements with bottom topography, television infrared observation satellite (TIROS)-N infrared images that provide sea surface temperature data (AVHRR) and productivity indices (SeaWiFS). MOCNESS samples will also enable us to identify prey species and to better describe the feeding habitats of right whales. Biopsy samples will be taken at the time of tagging to determine sex, examine genetic relationships, and test for contaminant levels.  The Central Scientific Issues of the North Pacific Marine
Research program suggest that we can learn more about the recent change in biological productivity in the Bering Sea ecosystem from right whales. We feel our research will provide substantial information regarding the seasonal movements of this
little-known whale, which may help in better understanding species interactions within the Bering Sea ecosystem. Lipid content and contaminant testing of the biopsy samples will address body condition and risk from pollutants.

An NPMR project</abstract>
      <purpose>A proposal "Foraging habitats and migration routes of the North Pacific right whale in the Bering Sea" supported by NPMR</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19990801</begdate>
          <enddate>20000731</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Planned</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>167</westbc>
        <eastbc>-163</eastbc>
        <northbc>67</northbc>
        <southbc>53</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Mammals</themekey>
        <themekey>Biology</themekey>
        <themekey>Oceanography</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Whales</themekey>
        <themekey>AVHRR</themekey>
        <themekey>MOCNESS</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Unknown</accconst>
    <useconst>Unknown</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Mate, Bruce R.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>2030 S. Marine Science Drive</address>
          <city>Newport</city>
          <state>OR</state>
          <postal>97365</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>541-867-0202</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>541-867-0128</cntfax>
        <cntemail>bruce.mate@hmsc.orst.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Mate, Bruce R.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>2030 S. Marine Science Drive</address>
          <city>Newport</city>
          <state>OR</state>
          <postal>97365</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>541-867-0202</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>541-867-0128</cntfax>
        <cntemail>bruce.mate@hmsc.orst.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19991206</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Unknown</metac>
    <metuc>Unknown</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
