<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>University of East Anglia - Climatic Research Unit, Norwich</origin>
        <pubdate>19970414</pubdate>
        <title>Thermohaline Oscillations in the LSG OGCM: Propagating Anomalies and Sensitivity to Parameterizations</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>New experiments are reported that extend previous studies of the internally generated variability found when the Hamburg LSG Ocean General Circulation Model is integrated under mixed  boundary conditions. All model integrations have stochastic forcing added to the freshwater flux to  excite the variability. It is demonstrated that the salinity anomalies that propagate around the meridional circulation of the Atlantic Ocean are merely signals emitted from the source of the variability in the Southern Ocean; they do not play an active role in its generation. It is the Southern Ocean flipﾖflop oscillator, as suggested by a previous study, that is the driving mechanism of the 320-yr period oscillations. A second mode of propagation is identified that may be related to the
periodicity of the oscillations: westward propagation of upper-ocean salinity anomalies around the coast of Antarctica. It is shown that this mode is driven by the same density-upwelling wave motion as reported elsewhere in the literature.

       The sensitivity of the simulated variability to changes in some of the modelﾒs numerical and physical algorithms is investigated. The computationally expensive step of retriangularizing the  matrix equation for the barotropic velocity can be done very infrequently without affecting the characteristics of the variability. Changing to a connective overturn parameterization that leaves  fewer residual instabilities has a small effect on the variability, while changing to one that mixes,  rather than interchanges, statically unstable water masses can reduce the magnitude of the  variability by up to 70%. The latter change, however, is attributed entirely to the different  freshwater flux forcing that the new parameterization implies. Using a more realistic haline and
thermal coupling between sea ice and the ocean also leads to greatly reduced internal variability on  the 320-yr timescale. Again, changes in surface fluxes implied by the alteration to the model are important, and these changes have implications for the flux adjustments necessary when the LSG  model is coupled to an atmosphere model. The results presented here indicate considerable scope for reducing such flux adjustments.</abstract>
      <purpose>To report on the Thermohaline Oscillations in the LSG OGCM: Propagating Anomalies and Sensitivity to Parameterizations</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19970414</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Meteorology</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Theragra Chalcogramma</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Osborn, Timothy J.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>University of East Anglia - Clmte. Resrch. Unit</address>
          <city>Norwich</city>
          <state />
          <postal />
          <country>United Kingdom</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Osborn, Timothy J.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>University of East Anglia - Clmte. Resrch. Unit</address>
          <city>Norwich</city>
          <state />
          <postal />
          <country>United Kingdom</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990205</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
