<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>
          U.S. Navy, Office of Naval Research
          <br />
          Carin Ashjian, Cabell Davis, and Scott Gallager of Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution
        </origin>
        <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
        <title>Characterization of Zooplankton Community and Size Composition in Relation to Hydrography and Circulation in the Sea of Japan</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>The zooplankton community of the Japan Sea remains poorly understood. Available data suggests that the northern Japan Sea has a low turnover and is characterized by a resident boreal community, while the southern half is characterized by rapid advective throughput of an oligotrophic community from the Kuroshio Current. It is possible that a transition zone community exists in the Subpolar Front separating the northern and southern Japan Sea. Presently there are no data on the basin-scale distributions of zooplankton collected concomitantly with hydrographic data, and the flux of zooplankton into and out of the straits has not been quantified.</p>
        <p>We propose to conduct two cruises to the Japan Sea, one during the stratified summer season (June/July 1999) and the second during the well-mixed winter season (February/March 2000), in order to obtain high resolution measurements of the basin-scale distributions of zooplankton abundance and taxonomic and size composition in relation to the hydrography, currents, light, fluorescence, and beam attenuation. Towyo transects will be made using the Video Plankton Recorder to determine distributions of zooplankton and associated variables over scales from centimeters to hundreds of kilometers. We will sample 5 transects extending across the sea from Japan to Russia, plus 4 tidally resolved transects across the four straits to quantify flux of zooplankton into and out of the Japan Sea.</p>
        <p>Part of the U.S. Office of Naval Research (ONR) supported research in the Japan/East Sea (JES) during 1998-2000. JES website URL: http://sam.ucsd.edu/onr_jes/onr_jes.html</p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>To provide a better understanding of how boreal and tropical zooplankton communities maintain themselves in a dynamic physical environment.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <mdattim>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>June/July 1999 and February/March 2000</caldate>
          </sngdate>
        </mdattim>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>128</westbc>
        <eastbc>143</eastbc>
        <northbc>54</northbc>
        <southbc>34</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Plankton</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Zooplankton</themekey>
        <themekey>Sea of Japan/East Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Transition Zone Community</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Contact Source.</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Source.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Ashjian, Carin</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (WHOI)</address>
          <city>Woods Hole</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02543</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>508-289-3457</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>cashjian@whoi.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Ashjian, Carin</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (WHOI)</address>
          <city>Woods Hole</city>
          <state>MA</state>
          <postal>02543</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>508-289-3457</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>cashjian@whoi.edu</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20041015</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Contact Source.</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Source.</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
