<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>
          Hideji Tanaka, Nancy Navis, Takeshi Onuma, Makoto Yamada, Yuzo Yamamoto, and Sadamasa Tsuchiya of Hokkaido National Fisheries Research Institute
          <br />
          North Pacific Anadromous Fish Commission (NPAFC)
        </origin>
        <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
        <title>
          Zooplankton Data Collected Aboard the R/V
          <em>Wakatake maru</em>
          in the Central North Pacific Ocean and Bering Sea during the Summer of 2002 (BASIS Japan)
        </title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
        <p>The Wakatake maru (666 gross tons) departed Kushiro on June 8, 2002 and returned on July 21, 2002. There were 28 experimental fishing stations during the cruise. Nineteen fishing stations were located in the vicinity of 180º longitude from 41ºN to 58º30ﾒN latitude, and nine operations were conducted in the international waters of the central Bering Sea.</p>
        <p>Macro-zooplankton were sampled with a remodeled NORPAC net (0.45 m ring diameter, 1.93 m net length, 0.33 mm mesh size) at 28 fishing stations and 6 transit stations located at intervals of 5º longitude from 150ºE to 160ºE. The net was towed vertically from 150 m to the surface. A calibrated flow meter was attached to the opening of the net in a position slightly off-center. Samples were fixed in 5% borax-buffered formalin in seawater.</p>
        <p>Large macro-zooplankton were collected at 28 fishing stations using an Ocean Research Institute (ORI) net (1.60 m diameter, 7.5 m in overall length, 0.67 mm mesh size). The ORI net was towed along side of the vessel at the surface at a speed of ca. 2 knots for 10 min around 23:00 hrs. Samples were fixed in 10% borax-buffered formalin in seawater. When NORPC or ORI net collected more sample material than the capacity of the sample bottle, then the total volume was measured and a subsample was retained.</p>
        <p>
          [Reference: Tanaka, H, N. Davis, T. Onuma, M. Yamada, Y. Yamamoto, and S. Tsuchiya. 2002. International salmon research aboard the R/V
          <em>Wakatake maru</em>
          in the central North Pacific Ocean and Bering Sea during the summer of 2002. (NPAFC Doc. 622). 21 p. Hokkaido National Fisheries Research Institute, Fisheries Research Agency, 116 Katsurakoi, Kushiro 085-0802, Japan.]  This report is available at http://www.npafc.org/BASIS/622(Japan).pdf
        </p>
      </abstract>
      <purpose>
        <p>
          To monitor the stock condition of salmon (
          <em>Oncorhynchus</em>
          spp.) in the central North Pacific Ocean and Bering Sea.
        </p>
      </purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20020608</begdate>
          <enddate>20020721</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>150</westbc>
        <eastbc>-178</eastbc>
        <northbc>58.5</northbc>
        <southbc>39</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Plankton</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Central North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Zooplankton</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Source.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>NPAFC Secretariat</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>889 West Pender Street, Suite 502</address>
          <city>Vancouver</city>
          <state>BC</state>
          <postal>V6C 3B2</postal>
          <country>Canada</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>604-775-5550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>604-775-5577</cntfax>
        <cntemail>secretariat@npafc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20050225</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>None</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Source.</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
