<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), Earth Sciences Information Center (ESIC), EROS Data Center</origin>
        <pubdate>1990-Present</pubdate>
        <title>Alaska (VHRR) Twice-Monthly Composites</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Data Type: Remotely Sensed Data;  Alaska AVHRR Data Set is comprised of twice-monthly maximum Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI) composites created from daily NOAA-11 satellite observations. The goal of the Alaska AVHRR project is to compile a comprehensive time series data set of calibrated, georegistered daily observations and twice monthly maximum NDVI composites for each annual growing season. This data set has applications for environmental monitoring and assessing impacts of global climate change. The NDVI composites include ten bands of information: AVHRR channels 1-5, maximum NDVI, satellite zenith, solar zenith, and relative azimuth. The daily observations, bands 1-9, have been calibrated to reflectance, scaled to byte data, and geometrically registered to the Albers Equal-Area Conic map projection. The tenth band is a pointer to identify the date and scene ID of the source daily observation (scene) for each pixel. All image processing was conducted using the Land Analysis System (LAS) software. Often when displaying data covering large areas, such as AVHRR data, it is beneficial to include an overlay of familiar linework as a location aid, or a mask to derive statistical data for regions. All of the line work images represent lines in raster format as 1 km cells and the strata are represented as polygons registered to the AVHRR data. The line work and raster polygon data sets include are the international boundaries, Alaskan roads and Trans-Alaska Pipeline, and a raster polygon mask of the State borders. The EROS Data Center standard product is a set of multiple CD-ROM.</abstract>
      <purpose>Unknown</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19900101</begdate>
          <enddate>20021231</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Ground Condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>172</westbc>
        <eastbc>-130</eastbc>
        <northbc>71.24</northbc>
        <southbc>51</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>North Pacific Ecosystem Metadatabase</themekt>
        <themekey>Geology</themekey>
        <themekey>Management</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Remotely Sensed Data</themekey>
        <themekey>AVHRR</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Data for one year is available on two CD-ROM's at a cost of $32.00 for each disc from USGS-EROS.</accconst>
    <useconst>None, request that USGS be noted as data source.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Oakley, Karen</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>1011 East Tudor Road</address>
          <city>Anchorage</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99503</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-786-3579</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>karen_oakley@nbs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Oakley, Karen</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>1011 East Tudor Road</address>
          <city>Anchorage</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99503</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-786-3579</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>karen_oakley@nbs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20020502</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Data for one year is available on two CD-ROM's at a cost of $32.00 for each disc from USGS-EROS.</metac>
    <metuc>None, request that USGS be noted as data source.</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
