<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Exxon Valdez Oil Spill Trustee Council, James Bodkin of the U.S. Geological Survey, Anchorage, Alaska and Thomas A. Dean of Coastal Resources Associates, Inc., Carlsbad, California.</origin>
        <pubdate>122003</pubdate>
        <title>Preliminary Benthos Survey</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This book references population abundance and species composition data of invertebrate species: Clinocardium californiensis, Clinocardium ciliatum, Macoma balthica, Macoma calcarea, Macoma carlottensis, Macoma inconspicua, Macoma moesta, Modiolus modiolus, and Mya spp. from Port Valdez, Prince William Sound, Alaska.

  The aforementioned data are referenced in citation: Feder, H. M., G. J. Mueller, M. H. Dick, and D. B. Hawkins.  1973.  Preliminary benthos survey.  In D.W. Hood, W.E. Shiels and E.J. Kelley (eds.), Environmental Studies of  Port Valdez, Inst. Mar. Sci. Occas. Publ. No. 3, University of Alaska, Fairbanks, Alaska.

  This literature was collected as part of a metadatabase that represents one or more nearshore resources (from physical attributes such as water and air, to birds and mammals).  Each entry is viewable in three formats, 1) a geospatial explicit format (ArcView 3.3) named GIS ArcView 3.3 Near GEM project, 2) a spreadsheet format (Excel 2002 and within ArcView) named GEM Nearshore Metadata Set, and 3) a ProCite database named GEM Nearshore Metadata References, which consists of references included in 1 and 2 above.  The ProCite database record number corresponds to the Excel Procite Number.  Reference Procite #326 for this literature's metadata.

  The metadata are maintained in digital format (ArcView 3.3, Excel 2002, and Procite) and are available from the Alaska Science Center, USGS in Anchorage, Alaska.

  For a detailed description of the three databases and the project, see "Bodkin, J. L., and T. Dean.  2003.  Alternative Sampling Designs for Nearshore Monitoring (Gulf Ecosystem Monitoring and Research Project G-030687), US Geological Survey, Alaska Science Center, Anchorage, Alaska." available on-line at http://www.evostc.state.ak.us/pdf/GEM_final_reports/030687.pdf.</abstract>
      <purpose>Part of the design effort of the "Alternative Sampling Designs for Nearshore Monitoring" (Gulf Ecosystem Monitoring and Research Project).  Provides a comprehensive historical perspective of locations and types of past studies conducted in the nearshore marine communities within Gulf of Alaska in the form of a geographical information system database.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <mdattim>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>Springs, falls, and winters of 1971 and 1972.</caldate>
          </sngdate>
        </mdattim>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Sample Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-146.41</westbc>
        <eastbc>-146.41</eastbc>
        <northbc>61.11</northbc>
        <southbc>61.11</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Population Abundance</themekey>
        <themekey>Species Composition</themekey>
        <themekey>Invertebrate Species</themekey>
        <themekey>Port Valdez, Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Prince William Sound</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Contact Source.</accconst>
    <useconst>Contact Source.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Bodkin, James L.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>1011 East Tudor Road</address>
          <city>Anchorage</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99503</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-786-3550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>james_bodkin@usgs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Bodkin, James L.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>1011 East Tudor Road</address>
          <city>Anchorage</city>
          <state>AK</state>
          <postal>99503</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>907-786-3550</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>james_bodkin@usgs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20040723</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Contact Source.</metac>
    <metuc>Contact Source.</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
