<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR)</origin>
        <pubdate>19970107</pubdate>
        <title>Terrain-Induced Turbulence over Lantau Island: 7 June 1994 Tropical Storm Russ Case Study</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Numerical simulations of terrain-induced turbulence associated with airflow
     over Lantau Island of Hong Kong are presented. Lantau is a relatively small
     island with three narrow peaks rising to between 700 and 950 m above mean
     sea level. This research was undertaken as part of a project to better
     understand and predict the nature of turbulence and shear at the new airport
     site on the island of Chek Lap Kok, which is located to the lee of Lantau.
     Intensive ground and aerial observations were taken from May through June
     1994, during the Lantau Experiment (LANTEX). This paper focuses on flow
     associated with the passage of Tropical Storm Russ on 7 June 1994, during
     which severe turbulence was observed.

       The nature of the environmental and topographic forcing on 7 June 1994
     resulted in the turbulence and shear being dominated by the combination of
     topographic effects and surface friction. High-resolution numerical
     simulations, initialized using local sounding data, were performed using the
     Clark model. The simulation results indicate that gravity-wave dynamics
     played a very minor role in the flow distortion and generation of turbulence.
     As a result of this flow regime, relatively high vertical and horizontal resolution
     was required to simulate the mechanically generated turbulence associated
     with Tropical Storm Russ.

       Results are presented using a vertical resolution of 10 m near the surface
     and with horizontal resolutions of both 125 and 62.5 m over local, nested
     domains of about 13ﾖ24 km on a side. The 125-m model resolution
     simulated highly distorted flow in the lee of Lantau, with streaks emanating
     downstream from regions of sharp orographic gradients. At this resolution the
     streaks were nearly steady in time. At the higher horizontal resolution of 62.5
     m the streaks became unstable, resulting in eddies advecting downstream
     within a distorted streaky mean flow similar to the 125-m resolution
     simulation. The temporally averaged fields changed little with the increase in
     resolution; however, there was a three- to fourfold increase in the temporal
     variability of the flow, as indicated by the standard deviation of the wind from
     a 10-min temporal average. Overall, the higher resolution simulations
     compared quite well with the observations, whereas the lower resolution
     cases did not. The high-resolution experiments also showed a much broader
     horizontal and vertical extent for the transient eddies. The depth of orographic
     influence increased from about 200 m to over 600 m with the increase in
     resolution. A physical explanation, using simple linear arguments based on the
     blocking effects of the eddies, is presented. The nature of the flow separation
     is analyzed using Bernoulliﾒs energy form to display the geometry of the
     separation bubbles. The height of the 80 m2 s2 energy surface shows
     eddies forming in regions of large orographic gradients and advecting
     downstream.

       Tests using both buoyancy excitation and stochastic backscatter to
     parameterize the underresolved dynamics at the 125-m resolution are
     presented, as well as one experiment testing the influence of static stability
     suppressing turbulence development. All these tests showed no significant
     effect. Implications of these results to the parameterization of mechanically
     induced turbulence in complex terrain are discussed.</abstract>
      <purpose>to show the Terrain-Induced Turbulence over Lantau Island: 7 June 1994 Tropical Storm Russ Case Study</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19970107</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Tropical Cyclones</themekey>
        <themekey>LANDSAT</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Clark, Terry L.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR)</address>
          <city>Boulder</city>
          <state>CO</state>
          <postal />
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Clark, Terry L.</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR)</address>
          <city>Boulder</city>
          <state>CO</state>
          <postal />
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990205</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
