<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (OAR), Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory (PMEL)</origin>
        <pubdate>1999</pubdate>
        <title>Upper Ocean Salinity Balance in the Western Equatorial Pacific</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The upper ocean salinity balance in the western equatorial Pacific warm pool was evaluated using up to 2.5 years of data (September 1991 through April 1994)
from the Coupled Ocean Atmosphere Response Experiment's (COARE's) enhanced monitoring array of moorings. At the central mooring site (0°, 156°E),
precipitation had a record length mean of 4.5 m yr, while evaporation had a mean of 1.4 m yr. This excess surface freshwater flux was balanced primarily by
vertical mixing (estimated as the residual of a salt budget calculation) and by zonal advection. For time scales between a month and 2.5 years, surface salinity
variability was dominated by zonal advection and only weakly correlated with precipitation, consistent with the concept of a zonally migrating fresh pool. The effects
of precipitation on local surface salinity variations were more apparent for time scales shorter than a month. Shallow rain "puddles" tended to form in a matter of
hours. However, due to the combination of mixing and advection, these precipitation generated freshwater puddles were typically short lived.</abstract>
      <purpose />
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo />
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>110</westbc>
        <eastbc>180</eastbc>
        <northbc>10</northbc>
        <southbc>-10</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Cronin, Meghan</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6449</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>Meghan.F.Cronin@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Cronin, Meghan</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-6449</cntvoice>
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail>Meghan.F.Cronin@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20010308</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
