<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>University of Maryland, Center for Environmental Science, Horn Point Laboratory</origin>
        <pubdate>19980224</pubdate>
        <title>Eddy Maintenance and Attrition in a Vertically Sheared Current under Arctic Ice</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Steady drift of an ice cover produces a vertically sheared current in the
     upper ocean of the Arctic. Under the ice cover, mesoscale shallow brine and
     freshening sources generate submerged anticyclones and cyclones,
     respectively. A submerged eddy extending deep into the water column
     experiences differential advections by the vertically sheared current.
     Interaction between subsurface eddies and the sheared current is examined
     using a three-dimensional numerical model in a coordinate system moving
     with the ice. The initial salinity field is in geostrophic balance with the sheared
     current, and a pulse of brine or freshening forcing produces an anticyclone or
     a cyclone. In a coordinate system moving with the ice, eddies are in a
     vertically sheared backward ambient current. To an observer looking into
     the direction of the backward ambient current, eddies move with the current
     and deflect to the right (left) for counterclockwise (clockwise) rotating
     eddies in both hemispheres. The lower half of the eddy always moves faster.
     The lateral movement can be explained by the KuttaﾖZhukhovski lift
     theorem. Differential advection produces eddy tilting and entails the
     development of a narrow jet following the moving eddy. The jet reduces
     eddy straining and tilting, and eddies disperse in cases of sizeable tilts.
     Driven by a vertically sheared current, cyclones are short-lived compared
     with anticyclones because the lateral movement of a cyclone exposes the
     lower part of the eddy into waters of weaker stratification. The results help
     explain the predominance of anticyclonic eddies under the Arctic ice.</abstract>
      <purpose>To report on the Eddy Maintenance and Attrition in a Vertically Sheared Current under Arctic Ice</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>19980224</begdate>
          <enddate />
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Publication Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None Planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>178</westbc>
        <eastbc>-168</eastbc>
        <northbc>67.5</northbc>
        <southbc>52</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Other</themekt>
        <themekey>Arctic</themekey>
        <themekey>Eddy</themekey>
        <themekey>Chukchi Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>Alaska</themekey>
        <themekey>Bering Sea</themekey>
        <themekey>North Pacific Ocean</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Check with Contributor</accconst>
    <useconst>Check with Contributor</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Chao, Shenn-Yu</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Univ of Maryland Cen. for Env. Sci.</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MD</state>
          <postal />
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Chao, Shenn-Yu</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>Univ of Maryland Cen. for Env. Sci.</address>
          <city>Cambridge</city>
          <state>MD</state>
          <postal />
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice />
        <cntfax />
        <cntemail />
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>While every effort has been made to ensure that these data are accurate and reliable within the limits of the current state of the art, NOAA cannot assume liability for any damages caused by any errors or omissions in the data, nor as a result of the failure of the data to function on a particular system. NOAA makes no warranty, expressed or implied, nor does the fact of distribution constitute such a warranty.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>19990205</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>Kimberly Bahl</cntper>
        </cntperp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Mailing and Physical Address</addrtype>
          <address>NOAA / AFSC / PMEL, 7600 Sand Point Way N.E.</address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98115</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-526-4314</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>206-526-6485</cntfax>
        <cntemail>kimberly.bahl@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metac>Check with Contributor</metac>
    <metuc>Check with Contributor</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
